The following is a conversation with
Jensen Huang, CEO of Nvidia, one of the
most important and influential companies
in the history of human civilization.
Nvidia is the engine powering the AI
revolution, and a lot of its success can
be directly attributed to Jensen's sheer
force of will and his many brilliant
bets and decisions as a leader,
engineer, and innovator.
This is the Lex Freedman podcast. And
now, dear friends, here's Jensen Huang.
You've propelled Nvidia into a uh new
era in AI, moving beyond his focus on
chip scale design to now rack scale
design. And I think it's fair to say
that uh winning for Nvidia for a long
time used to be about building the best
GPU possible. and you still do, but now
you've expanded that to extreme
co-design of GPU, CPU, memory,
networking, storage, power, cooling,
software, the rack itself, the pod that
you've announced, and even the data
center. So, let's talk about extreme
code design. What uh is the hardest part
of uh co-designing a system with that
many complex components and design
variables?
>> Yeah, thanks for that question. So first
of all, the reason why extreme code
design is necessary is because the
problem no longer fits inside one
computer to be accelerated by one GPU.
[gasps]
The problem that you're trying to solve
is you would like to go faster than the
number of computers that you add. So you
added, you know, 10,000 computers, but
you would like it to go a million times
faster.
Then all of a sudden you have to take
the algorithm,
you have to break up the algorithm, you
have to refactor it, you have to shard
the pipeline, you have to shard the
data, you have to shard the model.
[gasps]
Now all of a sudden when you distribute
the problem this way, not just scaling
up the problem, but you're distributing
the problem, then everything gets in the
way. This is the AMD doll's law problem
where the amount of speed up you have
for something depends on how much of the
total workload it is. And so if
computation represents 50% of the
problem and I sped up computation
infinitely like a million times you know
I only sped up the total workload by a
factor of two. Now all of a sudden, not
only do you have to distribute the
computation, you have to, you know,
shard the pipeline somehow. Uh you also
have to solve the networking problem
because you've got all of these
computers are all connected together.
And so distributed computing at the
scale that we do,
the CPU is a problem, the GPU is a
problem, the networking is a problem,
the switching is a problem, and
distributing the workload across all
these computers are a problem.
It's just a massively complex computer
science problem and so we just got to
bring every technology to bear otherwise
we scale up linearly
or we scale up based on uh the
capabilities of Moore's law which has
largely slowed because Dernard's scaling
has slowed. I'm sure there's trade-offs
there. Plus you have a completely
disperate disciplines here. I'm sure you
have specialists in each one of these
high bandwidth memory, the the
networking, the NVL link, the nyx, the
the optics and the copper that you're
doing, the power delivery, the cooling,
all that. I mean, there's like world
experts in each of those. How do you get
them in a room together to figure out
>> That's why my staff is so large.
>> What's the pro can you take me through
the process of the specialists and the
generalists? Like, how do you put
together the rack when you know this the
set of things you have to shove into a
rack together? Yeah,
>> like what does that process look like of
designing [clears throat] it all
together?
>> There's the the first question which is
what is extreme code design? You're
we're optimizing across the entire stack
of software from architectures to chips
to systems to system software to the
algorithms to the applications. That's
one layer. The second thing that you and
I just talked about is goes beyond CPUs
and GPUs and networking chips and scale
up switches and scale out switches. And
then of course you got to include power
and cooling and all of that because you
know all these computers are extremely
extremely power power hungry. They do a
lot of work and they're very energy
efficient but they in aggregate still
consume a lot of power. And so that's
one the first question is what is it?
The second question is why is it and we
just spoke about the reason you know you
want to distribute the workload so that
you can exceed the benefit of just
increasing the number of computers and
and then the third question is how is it
how do you do it
>> and and uh that's the that's kind of the
miracle of this company you know when
you're designing a computer you have to
have operating system of computers when
you're designing a company you should
first think about what is it that you
want the company to produce. You know, I
see a lot of companies organization
charts and they all look the same.
Hamburger organization charts, software
organization charts and car company
organization charts. They all look the
same. And it doesn't make any sense to
me. You know, the goal of au of a
company is to be the machinery, the
mechanism, the system that produces
the output and that output is the
product that we like to create. It is
also designed the architecture of the
company should reflect the environment
by which it exists. It almost directly
says what you should do with the
organization. My direct staff is 60
people. You know, I don't have one-on-
ones with them because it's impossible.
You can't have you can't have 60 people
on your staff if you're, you know, going
to get work done. And
>> so you still have 60 reports. You still
have more. Yeah. [laughter]
>> And most stars at least have a foot in
engineering.
almost all of them. There's experts in
memory, there's experts in CPUs, there's
experts in optical all Yeah. GPUs and
architecture, algorithms, design.
>> So, you constantly have an eye on the
entire stack and you're having to do
like intense discussions about the
design of the entire stack
>> and no conversation is ever one person.
That's why I don't do one-on- ones. We
present a problem and all of us attack
it, you know, because we're doing
extreme code design and literally the
company is doing extreme code design all
the time.
>> So even if you're talking about a
particular component like cooling
networking, everybody's listening in.
>> Yeah.
>> And they can contribute well this
doesn't work for the for the power
distribution. This doesn't exactly
>> this doesn't work for the for the
memory. This doesn't work for this.
>> Exactly. And whoever wants to tune out,
tune out.
>> [laughter]
>> You know what I'm saying? And the reason
for that is because because the people
who are on the staff, they they know
when to pay attention.
>> They're supposed, you know, something
they could have contributed to, they
didn't contribute to. I'm going to call
them out, you know, and so, hey, come
on, let's get in here.
>> So, as you mentioned, Nvidia is this
company that's adapting to the
environment.
>> So, at which point can you say,
>> did the environment change? be began
adapting sort of secretly
>> in the early days from GPU for gaming
maybe the early deep learning revolution
to we're now going to start thinking of
it as an AI factory. What does Nvidia do
is produces AI. Let's build a factory
that makes AI
>> I could I you could I could reason
through it just systematically. Um we
started out as as an accelerator company
but the problem with accelerators is
that the application domain is too
narrow. It has the benefit of being
incredibly optimized for the job. You
know, any specialist has that benefit.
The problem with intense specialization
is that of course your market reach is
narrower,
but that's that's even fine. The problem
is the market size also dictates your
R&D capacity. And your R&D capacity
ultimately dictates the influence and
impact that you can possibly have in
computing. And so when we first started
out in acceler as an accelerator, very
specific accelerator, we always we
always knew that that had that was going
to be our first step. We had to find a
way to become accelerated computing. But
the problem is when you become a
computing company, it's too general
purpose and it takes away from your
specialization. It turn I connected two
words
that are actually have fundamental
tension. The better computing company we
become, the worse we become as a
specialist. The more of a specialist,
the less capacity we have to do overall
computing. And so the that and I
connected those two words together on
purpose that the company has to find
that really narrow path step by step by
step to expand our aperture of computing
but not give up on the most important
specialization that we had. Okay. So the
first step that we took beyond
acceleration was we invented the
programmable pixel shader. So that was
the first step towards programmability.
our you know that was our first journey
towards moving into the world of
computing. The second thing that we did
was we we uh uh created uh we put FP32
into our shaders. That FP32 step IE
compatible FP32 was a huge step in the
direction of computing. It was the
reason why um all of the people who were
working on on um stream processors and
you know other types of data flow
processors discovered us and they say
hey all of a sudden you know we might be
able to use this GPUs that's incredibly
computationally intensive and it's now
you know compliant with it e I can take
my software that I was writing you know
previously on CPUs and I could you know
see about you know using the GPU for
that [clears throat]
and which led us to create put C on top
of FP32 was called we call CG that CG
path took us to eventually CUDA CUDA
step by step by step um uh we well
putting CUDA on GeForce that that was a
strategic decision that was very very
hard to do because it cost the company
enormous amounts of our profits and we
couldn't afford it at the time but we
did it anyways because we wanted to be a
computing company a computing company
has a computing architecture. A
computing architecture has to be
compatible across all of the chips that
we build.
>> Can you can you take me through that
decision? So, putting CUDA on GeForce
could not afford to do. Can you explain
that decision? Why
>> why boldly choose to do that anyway?
>> Can you explain that decision?
>> Excellent. That was that was the first I
would I would say that that was the
first um
the first strategic decision that that
is as close to an existential threat for
people who don't know it turned out to
be spoiler alert one of the most
incredibly brilliant decisions ever made
by a company. So CUDA turned out to be
an incredible foundation for computation
uh in this AI infrastructure world. So,
so you're just setting the context. It
turned out to be a good decision.
>> Yeah, it turned out to have been a good
decision. I think the So, so here here's
the way it went. So, we invented this
thing called CUDA and um uh it expanded
the the aperture of applications that
that we can accelerate with our
accelerator. The question is how do we
how do we attract developers to CUDA?
Because a computing platform is all
about developers. And developers
don't come to a computing platform just
because you know it could perform
something interesting. They come to a
computing platform because the install
base is large. Because a developer like
anybody else wants to develop software
that reaches a lot of people. So the
install base is in fact the single most
important part of an architecture. The
architecture could attract enormous
amounts of criticism. For example, no
architecture has ever attracted more
criticism than the x86.
You know, as as a less than less than
elegant architecture, but yet it is the
defining architecture of today. It it
gives you an example that in fact so
many risk architectures which were
beautifully architected
incredibly well-designed by some of the
brightest computer scientists in the
world largely failed and so I've given
you two examples where one is you know
one is elegant the other one's barely
aesthetic and so
yet x86 survived
>> install base is everything
>> install base defines an architecture not
everything else is secondary. Okay. And
so there were other architectures at the
time. CUDA came out, Open CL was here.
There were you know there's several
other competing architectures but the
the thing that the decision that we made
that was good was we said hey look
ultimately it's about um installed base
and what is the best way we could get a
new computing architecture into the
world.
By that time frame GeForce had become
successful. We were already selling
millions and millions of GeForce GPUs a
year. And we said, you know, we we ought
to put CUDA on GeForce
and put it into every single PC whether
customers use it or not and use it as a
starting point of cultivating our
installed base. Meanwhile, we'll go and
attract developers and we went to
universities and wrote books and taught
classes and put CUDA everywhere. And
eventually people discover and at the
time the PC was the primary computing
vehicle. There was no cloud and we could
put a supercomputer in the hands of
every researcher in school, every
scientist, you know, every engineering
school, every or every student in school
and eventually something amazing will
happen. Well, the problem was CUDA
increased our cost of that GPU, which is
a consumer product, so tremendously it
it completely consumed all of the
company's gross profit dollars. And so,
at the time, the company was probably,
you know, worth, I don't know, at the
time, eight,
was it like $8 billion or something
like$67 billion or something like that.
After we launched CUDA,
I recognized that it was going to add so
much cost, but it was something we
believed in. You know, our market cap
went down to like $1.5 billion. And so,
we were down we were down there for a
while and and uh we clawed our way way
back slowly, but we carried CUDA on
GeForce. I always say that Nvidia is the
house that GeForce built because it was
GeForce that took CUDA out to everybody.
Researchers, scientists, um they
discovered CUDA on GeForce because they
were all, you know, many of them were
gamers. Um many of them built their own
PCs anyways in a university lab. many of
them built clusters themselves you know
using using PC components and and so
that you know that's kind of how we got
going
>> and then that became the platform the
foundation for the deep learning
revolution
>> that was also another great great
observation yeah
>> that existential moment do you remember
like what were those meetings like what
were those discussions like deciding as
a company risking everything
>> well um I had I had to make it clear to
the board what we were trying to do and
and um uh the management team knew our
gross margins were going to get crushed.
So you could imagine a world where
GeForce would carry the burden of CUDA
and none of the gamers would appreciate
it and none of the gamers would pay for
it. You know, they only pay certain
price and it doesn't matter what your
cost is. And so that you know, we we
increased our cost by 50% and that con
consumed and we were a 35% gross margin
company. And so it it was a it was quite
a difficult decision to make, but you
could imagine that someday this could go
into workstations and it would go into
supercomputers and and in those segments
maybe we can capture more margin. Um so
you you could you could reason your way
into being able to afford this. Uh but
it still took it took a decade.
>> But that but that's more like
conversation with the board convincing
them. But you psychologically
>> because Nvidia has continued to make
bold bets
that predict the future and in part
especially now define the future. So I'm
almost looking for wisdom about how you
were able to make those decisions to
make leaps like that as a company.
Well, f first of all, um I'm informed by
by by a lot of curiosity. Uh at some
point there's a reasoning system
that that convinces me uh so clearly
this outcome will happen
that this will happen. And so I believe
I believe it in my mind. And when I
believe it in my mind, you know, you
know how it is. You manifest a future.
And that future is so convincing,
there's no way it won't happen. There's
a lot of suffering in in between, but
you've got to believe what you believe.
>> So you you you envision the future.
>> Yeah.
>> And you essentially from a sort of
engineering perspective manifest it.
>> Yeah. And and you you reason about how
to get there. You reason about why it it
must exist. Um and and um and you know,
I reason we all reason here. the
management team will reason about it.
All the people that I we spend a lot of
time reasoning about it. The thing the
thing that the next part of it is
probably a skill thing which is you know
oftentimes in leadership uh the
leadership stays quiet or they learn
about something and then they do some
manifesto and it's a brand new year and
somehow at the end of the year next year
we're going to have a brand new plan,
big huge layoff this way, big huge
organization change this way, new
mission statement, brand new logos, um
you know that kind of stuff. Um, we've
just never I never do things that way.
When I learn about something and it's
starting to influence how I think, I'll
make it very clear to everybody near me
that, you know, this this is
interesting. Um, this is going to make a
difference. Uh, this is going to impact
that. And I reason about things step by
step by step. often times I've already
made up my mind but I'll take every
possible opportunity external
information new insights new discoveries
uh new engineering you know revelations
uh new milestones developed I'll take
those opportunities and I'll use it to
shape everybody else's belief system and
I'm doing that literally every single
day I'm doing that with my board I'm
doing that with my management team I'm
doing that with my employees I'm trying
to shape their belief system such that
when I come the day I say, "Hey, let's
buy Melanox."
It's completely obvious to everybody
that we absolutely should. On the day
that on the day that I that I said, "Hey
guys, let's go all in on deep learning."
And let me tell you why. I've already
been laying down the bricks to different
organizations inside the company. every
organization and every everybody
many of the people might have heard
everything most of the company heard
hears of course pieces of it and on the
day that I announce it um
everybody's kind of bought into many
pieces of it and in a lot of ways I like
to announce these things and I imagine
um that that the employees are kind of
saying you know Jensen what took you so
long and and in fact I've been shaping
their belief system for some time and
therefore leadership
sometimes it looks like you're leading
from behind
>> but you've been shaping their you know
to the point where on the day that I
declared it 100% buy in but that's what
you want you want to bring everybody
along you know otherwise we announce
something about deep learning and
everybody goes what are you talking
about you know you announce something
about let's go allin on this thing and
and your your management team your board
your employees your customers, they're
kind of like, where's this coming from?
You know, this is insane. And so, so,
uh, GTC, in fact, if you go back in
time, you look at look at the keynotes,
I'm also shaping the belief system of my
partners and the industry and and I'm
using that to shape, you know, the
belief system of my own employees and
and and so by the time that I announce
something, like, for example, we just
now we just announced Grock, we've been
late. I've been talking about the
stepping stones for two and a half
years. You guys just go back and oh my
gosh, they've been talking about it for
two and a half years. And so I've been
laying the foundation step by step by
step. So when the time comes you
announce it, everybody's, you know, what
took you so long?
>> But it's not just inside the company.
You're shaping the landscape, the
broader global landscape of innovation.
Like putting those ideas out there, you
really are manifesting reality.
>> We don't build computers. We actually
don't build clouds. We don't, as it
turns out, we're a computing platform
company and so nobody can buy anything
from us. That's the weird thing. You
know, we ver we vertically
design vertically integrate to design
and optimize, but then we open up the
entire platform at every single layer to
be integrated into other companies
products and services and clouds and
supercomputers and OEM computers and and
so the amazing thing is I can't do what
I do without having convinced them
first. And so most of GTC is about
manifesting a future that by the time
that we my product is ready, they're
going what took you so long? [laughter]
Yeah. Uh so one of the things you've
been a believer for a long time is uh
scaling laws broadly defined. So are you
still a believer in the in the scaling
laws?
>> Yeah, we have more scaling laws now.
>> So I think uh you've outlined four of
them with pre-training, post- training,
test time, and agentic scaling. What do
you think when you think about the
future, deep future and the near-term
future, what are the blockers that
you're most concerned about that keep
you up at night that you have to
overcome in order to keep scaling?
>> Well, we can go back and reflect on what
people thought were blockers.
>> Mhm. So in the beginning we were the
first the pre pre-training scaling law
you know people thought uh well
rightfully so that the amount of data
that we have high quality data that we
have um will limit the intelligence that
we achieve and that scaling law was an
important very important scale law the
larger the model the correspondently
more data uh results in a better with a
results in a smarter AI and so that was
pre-training and Ilas Susker Ilas
we're out of data or something like
that. Pre-training is over or something
like that. The the industry panicked,
you know, that this is the end of AI.
And of course, of course, that's that's
obviously not true. Um, we're going to
keep on scaling the amount of data that
we h have to to train with. A lot of
that data is probably going to be
synthetic. And that also confused
people, you know, and and what people
don't realize is they've kind of
forgotten that most of the data that
that we are training uh that we teach
each other with, inform each other with
this is synthetic. You know, I it's
synthetic because it didn't come out of
nature. You created it. I'm consuming
it. I modify it, augment it, I
regenerate it, somebody else consumes
it. And [snorts] so so we've now reached
a level where AI is able to
take ground truth, augment it,
enhance it, synthetically generate an
enormous amount of data and that part of
post training um continues to scale. And
so the amount of data that we could use
that is human generated will be smaller
and smaller and smaller. the amount of
data that we use to uh train model uh uh
is going to continue to scale to the
point where we're no longer limited
training is no longer limited by data is
now limited by compute and the reason
for that is most of the data is
synthetic then the next phase is uh test
time and um I I still remember people
people telling me that inference oh yeah
that's easy pre pre-training that's hard
these are giant systems that people are
talking about inference must be easy and
so inference chips are going to be
little tiny chips and you know they're
not they're not like Nvidia's chips oh
those are going to be complicated and
expensive and you know we could make and
this is and in the future inference is
going to be the biggest market and it's
going to be easy and we're going to
commoditize and you know everybody can
build their own chips and and and that
was always illogical to me because
inference is thinking and I think
thinking is hard thinking is way harder
than reading.
>> You know, pre-training is just
memorization and generalization, you
know, and looking for patterns and
relationships. You're reading and
reading versus thinking, reasoning,
solving problems, taking un unexplored
experiences, new experiences, and
breaking it down into de decomposing it
into, you know, solvable pieces that we
then go off either through first
principal reasoning or, you know,
through through uh previous examples,
prior experiences, you know, or or or
just uh uh exploration. and and search
and you know trying different things and
that whole process of post of of test
time scaling. Uh inference is really
about thinking and and it's about
reasoning. It's about planning. It's
about search. It's about and so how
could that possibly be computed? And we
were absolutely right about that you
know so so test time scaling is
intensely comput intensive.
Then the question is okay now we're at
inference and we're at test time
scaling. What's beyond that? Well,
obviously
uh we have now created you know one
agentic person and that one agentic
person has a large language model that
we've now we've now you know developed.
But during test time, that agentic
system goes off and does research and
bangs on databases and it goes on and
you know uses tools and one of the most
important things it does is spins off
and spawns off a whole bunch of sub
aents which means we're now creating
large teams. It's so much easier to
scale Nvidia by hiring more employees
than it is to scale myself.
>> And so the next scaling law is the
agentic scaling law. It's kind of like
multip multiplying
AI. Multiplying AI, we could spin off
agents as fast as you want to spin off
agents. And so, you know, I you have
four scaling laws. And and as we use the
a agentic systems, they're going to
create a lot more data. They're going to
create a lot of experiences. Some of it
we're going to say, "Wow, this is really
good. We ought to memorize this."
>> That data set then comes all the way
back to pre-training. We memorize and
generalize it. We then refine it and
fine-tune it back into post training.
Then we enhance it even more with test
time, you know, in the agent agents
agentic systems, you know, put it onto
the indust industry. And so this loop,
the cycle is going to go on and on and
on. It kind of comes down to basically
intelligence is going to scale by one
thing and it's compute. But there's a
tricky thing there that you have to
anticipate and predict which is some of
these components. It requires different
kind of hardware to really do it
optimally. So you have to anticipate
where the AI innovation is going to
lead. For example, mixture of experts
with sparity.
>> Perfect.
>> With hardware, you can't just pivot on a
week's notice. You have to anticipate
what that's going to look like. That's
>> that's so scary and difficult to do,
right? For example, uh these AI model
architectures are being invented about
once every six months.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
Right. And uh system architectures and
hardware architectures
kind of every 3 years. And so you need
to anticipate what likely is going to
happen, you know, 2 3 years from now.
And there's a couple ways that you could
do that. First of all, we could do
research internally ourselves. And
that's one of the reasons why we have
basic research. We have applied
research. We create our own models. And
so we have we have hands-on life
experience right here. This is part of
the code design that I'm talking about.
>> We're also the only AI company in the
world that works with literally every AI
company in the world. And to the extent
that we can um uh we try to get a sense
of of what are the challenges that
people are experiencing.
>> So you're listening to the whispers
across the industry, the adabs.
>> That's right. You got to listen and and
learn from everybody and have a have a
and then the the last part is to have an
architecture that's that's flexible that
can adapt and move with the wind and one
of the benefits of of CUDA is that it's
you know on the one hand an incredible
accelerator on the other hand it's
really flexible and so that balance
incredible balance between
specialization
otherwise we can't accelerate the the
CPU versus generalization so that we can
adapt with changing algorithms. That's
really really important. That's the
reason why why um CUDA has been so
resilient um on the one hand and yet we
continue to enhance it. We're at CUDA
13.2 and so we're invol evolving the
architecture so fast that we can stay
with you know with with the modern al
algorithms. Um for example
uh when mixture of experts came out uh
that's the reason why we had MVLink 72
instead of MVLink 8. We could now take
an entire 4 trillion 10 trillion
parameter model and put it in one
computing domain as if it's running on
one GPU. Um I people probably didn't
notice I said it but if you look at the
architecture of the Grace Blackwell
racks it was completely focused on doing
one thing processing the LLM.
All of a sudden one year later you're
looking at a Vera Rubin rack. It has
storage accelerators. It has this
incredible new CPU called Vera. [snorts]
It has Vera Rubin and MVLink72 to run
the LLMs. It also has this new
additional rack called Gro. And so this
entire rack system is completely
different than the previous one and it's
got all these new components in it. And
the reason for that is because the last
one was designed to run
large language models inference and this
one is to run agents and agents bang on
tools and Obviously the design of the
system
had to have been done before claude
code, codeex, open claw. So you were
anticipating the future essentially and
that that comes from what? From the
whispers, from the understanding what
all the state of the artist is.
>> No, it's it's easier than that. Uh you
you just reason about it. Uh first of
all just reason
no matter no matter what happens at some
point in order for that large language
model to be a digital worker. Let's just
let's just use that metaphor. Let's say
that we want the LM to be a digital
worker. What does it have to do? It has
to access ground truth. That's our file
system. It has to be able to do
research. It doesn't know everything. We
don't have and I don't want to wait
until this AI becomes, you know,
universally smart about everything past,
present, and future before I make it
useful. And so therefore, I might as
well let it go do research. It's
obviously if it wants to help me, it's
got to use my tools. You know, a lot of
people would say, you know, um AI is
going to completely destroy software. We
don't need software anymore. We don't
even need tools anymore. That's
ridiculous. Let's let's use the let's
use a thought experiment. Uh, and you
could just sit there, enjoy a glass of
whiskey and and think about all these
things and it would become completely
obvious like if I were to create
the most amazing ro the most amazing
agent that we can imagine in the next 10
years, let's say be a humanoid robot. If
that human or robot were to be created,
is it more likely that the human or
robot comes into my house and uses the
tools that I have to do the work that it
needs to do? Or does his hand turns into
a 10- pound hammer in one instance,
turns into a scalpel in another
instance, and in order to boil water, it
beams, you know, microwaves out of its
fingers, you know, or is it more likely
just to use the microwave, you know, and
the first time it goes up to the
microwave. It probably doesn't know how
to use it. But that's okay. It's
connected to the internet. It reads the
manual of this microwave, reads it
instantly, becomes an expert, and so
uses it.
>> And so I I think the I just described in
fact almost all of the
properties of Open Claw.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, that it's going to use tools,
that it's going to access files, it's
going to be able to do research, it has
IO subsystem. And when you're done
reasoning through it, reasoning about it
through through it in that way, um then
you say, "Oh my gosh, the impact to the
future computing is deeply profound."
And the reason for that is I think we've
just reinvented the computer. And then
now you say, "Okay, when did we reason
about that? When did we reason about
Open Claw?" If you take the Open Claw
schematic that I used at GTC,
you will find it two years ago.
Literally two years ago at GTC, I was
talking about Asgentic systems that
exactly reflect open claw today and and
of course the confluence of of many
things had to happen. First of all, we
needed claude and and GPT and you know
all of these models to reach a level of
capability. So so their innovation and
their breakthroughs and their continual
advances was really important. And then
of course somebody had to create a an
open- source you know um project that
that uh was sufficiently robust you know
and sufficiently complete and that we
can all we can all put to put to work
and and I think openclaw did for did for
agentic systems what chat GPT did for
generative systems and and I just think
it's a very big deal.
>> Yeah, it's a really special moment. I'm
not exactly sure why it captured
so much of the world's attention, but it
did more than cloud code and codeex and
so on because consumers could reach it.
>> Sure. Yeah. But there there's also so
much of this is vibes and and Peter uh I
had a podcast with him. He's a wonderful
human being. So part of it is also the
humans that represent the thing. Part of
it is memes and the
>> cuz we're all trying to figure it out.
There's really serious and complicated
security concerns about when you have
such powerful technology, how do you
hand over your data so they can do
useful stuff, but then there's scary
things associated with that. And we as a
civilization, as individual people and
as a civilization figuring out how to
find that right balance.
>> Yeah, we we uh we jumped on it right
away and we sent a bunch of security
experts this way
>> and we did this thing called Open Shell.
It's it's already been integrated into
into open claw
>> and Nvidia put forward Nemo claw.
>> Yep. Exactly.
>> The install is super easy. It makes sure
that uh it's secure.
>> We give you two out of three rights.
Agentic systems can can access sensitive
information. It can execute code and it
can communicate externally.
>> Mhm.
>> We could keep things safe if we gave you
two out of those three capabilities at
any time, but not all three. And out of
those two out of three capabilities, we
also give you access control based on
based on um whatever rights that you're
given by enterprise. And then we
connected to a policy engine that all
these enterprises already have. And so
um we're going to try to do our best to
to uh help Open Claw become a a better
claw. So you eloquently explained how we
have a long history of blockers that we
thought were going to be blockers and we
overcame them. But now looking into the
future, what do you think might be the
blockers now that it's clear that agents
will be everywhere? So it's obviously
we're going to need compute. So what is
going to be the blocker for that
scaling? Power is a concern, but it's
not the only concern. But that's the
reason why we're pushing so hard on
extreme code design so that we can
improve the tokens per second per watt
orders of magnitude every single year.
And so in the last 10 years, Moors law
would have progressed computing about a
100 times in the last 10 years. We
progressed and scaled up computing by a
million times in the last 10 years. And
so we're going to keep on we're going to
keep on doing that through extreme code
design. Um so energy efficiency per per
watt completely affects the revenues of
a company. It affects the revenues of a
factory and we're just we're just going
to push that to the limit so that we can
keep on driving token cost down as fast
as we can. you know, the our computer
price is going up, but our token
generation effectiveness is going up so
much faster that token cost is coming
down. It's just it it's coming down an
order of magnitude every year.
>> So power that's an interesting one. So
the the way to try to get around the
power blocker is to try to with the
tokens per second per watt try to make
it more and more efficient. Of course,
there's the question, how do we get more
power?
>> We should also get more power.
>> That's a really complicated one. And
you've talked about small module nuclear
power plants. There's all kinds of ideas
for energy. Uh how much does it keep you
up at night? Uh the the bottlenecks in
the supply chain of AI like ASML with
EUV lithography machines, TSMC with
advanced packaging like cos and uh SK HX
with high bandwidth memory all all the
time and we're working on all the time.
No company in history has ever grown at
a scale that we're growing while
accelerating that growth. It's
incredible.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's hard for people to even
understand this in the overall world of
AI computing. We're increasing share.
And so supply chain upstream and
downstream are really important to us. I
spent a lot of time um informing all the
CEOs that I work with what are the
dynamics that's going to cause uh the
growth to continue or even accelerate.
It's part of the reasons why to the
entire right hand side of me were CEOs
of practically the entire IT industry
upstream and practically the entire
[gasps]
infrastructure industry downstream. Mhm.
And they were all there were several
hundred CEOs and I don't think there's
ever been keynotes where several hundred
CEOs show up. And and [clears throat]
part of it is I'm telling them about our
business condition now. I'm telling them
about the growth drivers in the very
near future and what's happening. And
I'm also describing where are we going
to go next so that they could use all of
this information and all of the dynamics
that are here to inform how they want to
invest.
And so so I I inform them that way like
I inform my own employees. And then of
course then I make trips out to them and
make sure that hey listen I want you to
know this quarter, this coming year,
this next year these things are going to
happen and and if you look at the CEOs
of the DRAM industry um the number one
DRAM in the in the world was DDR memory
for CPUs in data centers. About three
years ago, I was able to convince
several of the CEOs that even though at
the time HBM memory was used quite
scarcely, you know, and and barely by
supercomputers,
um that this was going to be a
mainstream memory for data centers in
the future. And at first it sounded
ridiculous, but several of the CEOs
believed me and decided to invest in
building HBM memories. Another memory
was rather odd to put into a data center
is the low power memories that we use
for cell phones. And we wanted them to
adapt them for supercomputers in the
data center. And they go, cell phone
memory for supercomputers. And I
explained to them why. Well, look at
these two memories, LPDDR5,
HBM4.
The volumes are so incredible. All three
of them had record years in history. And
these are these are 45 year old
companies. And so, you know, I that's
part of my job is to
inform and shape,
inspire,
you know. So, you're not just
manifesting the the future and maybe
inspiring Nvidia, the the the different
engineers of the company. You're you're
manifesting the supply chain of the
future. So you're having conversations
with TSMC, with ASML,
>> upstream, downstream,
>> upstream, downstream. So that's the
thing.
>> GEV, Caterpillar.
>> Yeah, that's downstream from us. Yeah.
Yeah. There you go.
>> Yeah. The whole thing. I mean, but
that's so
>> there's so much incredibly difficult
engineering that happens in the the
entire semiconductor industry. And it's
just feels scary how intricate the
supply chain is, how many components
there are, but it works somehow.
Exactly. The deep science, the deep
engineering, the incredible
manufacturing, and so much of the
manufacturing is already robotics, but
we have a couple of hundred suppliers
that contribute the technology that goes
into our 1.3 million component rack.
Mhm.
>> Each rack is 1.3 one and a half million
components. There are 200 suppliers
across the Vera Rubin rack.
>> So, it's interesting that you don't list
that as the thing that keeps you up at
night in the list of blockers.
>> But I'm doing I'm doing all the things
necessary to
>> Okay.
>> See, I can go to sleep because I checked
it off. I said, "Okay, you know, I I go
I I can go to sleep and I go, well,
let's see what um re let's reason about
this. What's important for us?" Um
because okay let's reason about this uh
because we changed the system
architecture from the original DGX1 that
you remembered to uh MVLink 72 rack
scale computing.
>> Mhm.
>> What's going to what does that what does
that mean? What does that mean to uh
software? What does that mean to
engineering? What does that mean uh to
how we design and test and what does
that mean to the supply chain? Well, one
of the things that it meant was we moved
um supercomput superco computer
integration at the data center into
supercomputer manufacturing in the
supply chain.
>> Mhm.
If you're doing that, you also have to
recognize you're going to move one and
and if if if you're if you're, you know,
total footprint of whatever data center
you're going to build, let's say you
would like to have, you know, 50 gawatts
of supercomputers that are running
simultaneously
and it takes one week to manufacture
that 50 gawatts of supercomputers. Then
each week in the supply chain, the
supercomputers are going to need a
gigawatt of power. And so so we're going
to need the supply chain to increase the
amount of power it has to build test to
build and test the supercomputers in the
supply chain before I ship it.
>> Well, MVLink72 literally builds
supercomputers in the supply chain and
ships them two, three tons at a time per
rack. It used to be come they used to
come in parts and we used to assemble
them inside the data center. But that's
impossible now because MVLink 72 is so
dense. And so that's an example. And I
would have to go into, you know, I fly
into the supply chain, go meet my
partners, and hey, I said, guess what?
So here's what we're going to do with
this is the way we used to build our
DGXs. We're going to build them this
way. This is going to be so much better
because we're going to need them for
inference. The market for inference is,
you know,
coming. The inflection point for
inference is coming. It's going to be a
big market. And so I first explain to
them what's going on, why it's going to
happen, and then I then I ask them to
make several billion dollars of capital
investments each
and because they, you know, they trust
me and and I I I'm very respectful of
them and I I give them every opportunity
to question me and I spend time to
explain things to people and I reason
about it. I draw them pictures and I
reason about it in first principles and
by by the time I'm done with them
there's no what to do.
>> So it's a lot of is about relationships
and building a shared view of the
future.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh but do you worry about certain
bottlenecks? I mean what are the biggest
bottlenecks in the supply chain? Are are
you worried about it ASML V tooling? Are
you are you worried about the the
packaging co-as packaging of TSMC about
how fast it could scale? like you said,
you're not only growing incredibly fast,
you're accelerating a growth. So it it
it feels like every everybody in the
supply chain and those are certainly
bottlenecks would have to scale up.
>> Are you having conversations with them
like how can you scale up faster?
>> Do you worry about it?
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> Because because I told them what I
needed, they understood what I need.
They told me what they're going to go do
and I believe in what they're going to
do.
>> Interesting. That's great to hear. So
maybe if we can just linger on the power
for a little bit. Uh what are your hopes
for how to solve the energy problem? One
of the areas le that I'm um that I would
love I would love love us to talk about
and just get the message out. You know
um our our our power grid is designed
for the worst case condition with some
margin.
Well, 99% of the time we're nowhere near
the worst case condition because the
worst case condition is a few days in
the winter, a few days in the summer and
extreme weather. Most of the time we're
nowhere near the worst case condition
and we're probably running around call
it 60% of peak. And so 99% of the time
our power grid has excess power and
they're just sitting idle. But they have
to be there sitting idle because just in
case when the time comes hospitals have
to be powered and you know
infrastructure has to be powered and
airports have to run and so on so forth.
And so the question that I have is
whether we could go and um help them
understand and create contractual
agreements and design computer
architecture systems, data centers such
that when they need
um the maximum power for infrastructure
in society that the data centers would
get less.
>> But that's in a very rare instance
anyways. And during that time, we either
have our backup generator for that
little part of it or we just have our
computers shift the workload somewhere
else or we have the computers just run
slower. You know, we could degrade our
performance, reduce our power
consumption and provide for, you know,
slightly longer latency response, you
know, when somebody asks for, you know,
asked for an answer. And so I think that
that that way of using computers of
building data centers instead of
expecting 100% uptime
and these contracts that are really
really quite rigorous it's putting a lot
of pressure on the grid to be able to
now they're going to have to increase
from their maximum. I just want to use
their excess. It's just sitting there.
Yeah. That's not talked about enough. So
what's what's this what's stopping
there? Is it regulation? Is it
bureaucracy?
>> I think it's it's a throughway problem.
Uh it starts with the end customer. The
end customer puts puts requirements on
the data centers that they can never
not be available. Okay. So that the end
customer expects perfection. Now in
order to deliver that perfection, you
need a combination of backup generators
and your grid power supplier to deliver
on perfection. And so everybody's got to
have 69s.
>> Well, I think first of all, right now,
we ought to have everybody understand
that when the customer asks for these
things, you got somebody, you have
somebody in your data center operations
team disconnected from the CEO. I bet
the CEO doesn't know this. I'm going to
talk to all the CEOs. The CEOs are
probably not paying any attention to the
contracts that are being signed. And so
everybody wants to sign the best
contract of course and they go down to
the cloud service providers and the
contract the the two contract
negotiators that are you I could just
see them now
>> you know negotiating these multi-year
contracts both sides want you know the
best contract as a result
the CSPs then have to go down to the
utilities and they expect the nine the
69s and so I think I think the first
thing is just make sure that that all of
the customers, the CEOs of the customers
realize what they're asking for. Now,
the second thing is we have to build
data centers that gracefully degrade.
And so, if the power, if the utility of
the grid tells us, listen, we're going
to have to back you down to about 80%.
We're going to say that's no problem at
all.
>> Mhm.
>> We're just going to move our workload
around. We're going to make sure that
data is never lost, but we can reduce
the computing rate and use less energy.
the quality of service degrades a little
bit for the critical workloads I shift
that somewhere else right away so I
don't have that problem and so you know
whoever whichever data center still has
100% uptime and so how difficult of an
engineering problem is that the smart
dynamic allocation of power in the data
center
>> as soon as you could specify you could
engineer it [laughter]
beautifully put
so long as it obeys the laws of physics
on first principles I think we're good
>> what was the third thing you were
mentioning um so the Second thing is the
the data centers
>> and the third thing is we need the
utilities
to also recognize that this is an
opportunity
>> and and instead of instead of saying
look um it's going to take me 5 years to
increase my grid capability uh if you if
you have if you're willing to take power
of this level of guarantee
I can make them available for you next
month and at this price and so if
utilities He's also offered more
segments of power delivery promises,
then I think everybody will figure out
what to do with it. Yeah. But there's
just way too much waste in the in the
grid right now. We we should go after
it.
>> Uh you've uh highly lauded Elon and uh
Xi's accomplishment in Memphis in
building um Colossus Supercomputer
probably in record time in just 4
months. It's now at 200,000 GPUs and
growing very quickly. Is there something
that you could speak to the understand
about his approach that's instructive to
the broadly to all the data center
creators that's um that enabled that
kind of accomplishment his approach to
engineering his approach to the whole
management of construction everything
first of all Elon is deep in so many
different topics um uh yet he's also a
really good systems thinker
[clears throat]
>> and so he's able to think through
multiple disciplines and and um uh he
obviously
uh pushes things questions everything
whether number one is it necessary
number two does it have to be done this
way and number you know does it have
does it have to take this long and and
so so he he has he has the he has the
ability uh to question everything uh to
the point where everything is down to
its minimal amount that's necess
necessary. You can't take anything else
out and and yet yet the the uh the the
the the necessary um capabilities of the
product retains, you know, and so he's
he is as minimalist as you could
possibly imagine and he does it at a
system system scale. Um I I also love
the fact that he he is um he is
represented he he is he is present at
the point of action.
>> Mhm. you know, he'll just go there and
if there's a problem, he'll just go
there and show me the problem. You know,
when you do all of this in combination,
you overcome a lot of previous this is
just the way we do it.
>> Um, you know, I'm I'm waiting for them.
I, you know, I mean, just everybody has
a lot of excuses. And and so and then
and then the last thing is when when you
act personally with so much urgency, uh
it causes everybody else to act with
urgency, you know, and and every
supplier has a lot of customers going
on. Every supplier has a lot of projects
going on. And he he make it he made it
he makes it his business that he's the
top priority of everybody else's, you
know, projects. And so he does that by
demonstrating it.
>> Yeah. I've been in a bunch of those
meetings. is it's fun to watch cuz
really not enough people ask the
question like okay so uh can this be
done a lot faster and how why does it
have to take this long yeah
>> and then that becomes an engineering
question often and yes I think when you
get the ground truth of actually I
remember um one of the times I was
hanging out with him he literally is
going through the entire process how to
plug in cables into a rack and he's was
working with engineer on the ground
that's doing that task and he's just
trying to understand what does that
process look like so it can be less
errorprone
and just building up that intuition from
every single task involved in uh putting
together the data center. You
[clears throat]
start to immediately get a sense at the
detailed scale and at the broad system
scale of where the inefficiencies are
and so you can make it more and more and
more efficient. Plus, you have the big
hammer of being able to say, "Let's do
it totally different."
>> Yeah.
>> And remove all possible blockers.
>> That's right.
>> Is there parallels in the Nvidia extreme
systems code design approach that you
see in the way Elon approaches systems
engineering?
>> Well, first of all, the code design is a
ultimate systems engineering problem.
And so, we approach we approach the work
that we do from that first from that
principle. Um the other thing that we do
uh and this is this is a a philosophy
that a thought
a a state of mind I guess a method that
I started uh 30 years ago and it's
called the speed of light. The speed of
light is not just about the speed. Speed
of light is my my shorthand for u what's
what's the limit of what physics can do.
And so every single everything
everything that we do is compared
against the speed of light. Um memory
speed uh math speed uh power cost time
effort number of people manufacturing
cycle time. And uh when you think about
latency versus throughput, uh when you
think about cost versus throughput, cost
versus capacity, all of these things, uh
you test against the speed of light to
achieve all of these different
constraints separately.
And then when you consider it together,
you know, you have to make compromises
because a system that achieves extremely
low latency versus achie a system that
achieves very high throughput are
architected fundamentally differently.
But you want to know what's the speed of
light of a system that achieves high
throughput? What's the speed of light of
a system that achieves low latency? And
then when you think about the total
system, you can make trade-offs. And so
I I force everybody to think about
what's this what the f the first
principles the limits
>> the physical limits
um for everything before we you know
before we uh do anything and and we test
everything against that and so that's a
good frame of mind I don't love the
other methods which is continuous
improvement
>> the the problem with continuous
improvement it it first of all you
should engineer something from first
principles at the speed you know with
speed of light thinking limited only by
physical limits and and physics limits
and um after that of course you would
improve it over time um but I don't like
going into a problem and somebody says
hey you know it takes 74 days to do this
today
>> right now and um we can do it for you in
72 days
>> you know I rather strip it all back to
zero
>> and so first of all explain to me why
it's 74 is in the first place and let's
know let's think about what's possible
today and if I were to to build it
completely from scratch you know how
long would it take often times you'd be
surprised and might come to 6 days now
the rest of the 6 days to 74 could be
very wellreasoned and compromises and
you know cost reductions and all kinds
of different things but at least you
know what they are and then now that you
know that six days possible
Then the conversation from 74 to 6
surprisingly much more effective
>> in such incredibly complex systems that
you're working with is simplicity
sometimes a good huristic to to reach
for I mean if I can just
I mean the pod the Vera Rubin pod that
you announced is just incredible uh
we're talking about seven chips seven
chip types five purpose-built rack types
40 racks 1.2 two quadrillion
transistors, nearly 20,000 Nvidia dies,
over 1100 Ruben GPUs, 60 exoflops, 10
pabytes per second of scale bandwidth.
Uh, that's all just one
>> that's just one pod.
>> That's just [laughter]
>> Yeah, that's just one pod.
>> I mean, so you have the and then even
the the NVL72 rack alone is 1.3 million
components, 1300 chips, 4,000 lb crammed
into a single 19inch wide rack. And Lex,
we'll probably kind of crank out about
200 of these pods a week just to put in
perspective
>> the the amount of different components.
I suppose simplicity is impossible, but
is that a metric that you kind of reach
for in trying to design things?
>> You know, the phrase the phrase that I
use most often is we we need things to
be as complex as necessary but as simple
as possible. And and so the question is
is all that complexity there necessary?
And we ought to test for that and we
ought to challenge that. And then after
that everything else above it, you know,
it's gratuitous.
>> But it's some of the most incredible
semiconductor industry broadly, but what
Nvidia is doing uh
some of the greatest engineering in
history. So these systems are just truly
truly marvels of engineering.
>> It is the most complex computer the
world has ever made. Yeah, the
engineering teams. I mean, I don't it's
not a competition, but I don't know if
if it was like an Olympics of uh
engineering teams. I mean, TSMC does
incredible engineering. Like I said,
ASML at every scale, but Nvidia is going
to give them a run for their money.
>> Just incredible, incredible teams,
>> gold medal medalist in every single in
every single sport, all assembled right
here
>> and have to work together and report
directly to you. This is wonderful. Uh
you've recently traveled to China.
Uh so it's interesting to ask you uh
China's been incredibly successful in
building up its technology sector. What
do you understand about um how China is
able to over the past 10 years build so
many incredible world-class companies,
world-class engineering teams and just
this technology ecosystem
>> that produces so many um incredible
products. whole bunch of reasons for
well first of all let's let's start
let's start with some facts 50% of the
world's AI researchers are Chinese
plus or minus and they're mostly in
China still we have many of them here
but there's amazing researchers still in
China um they their tech industry showed
up at precisely the right time at the
time of the mobile cloud era uh their
way of contributing was software and So
this is a country's in incredible
science and math. Uh really well
educated kids. Um uh their tech industry
was created during the era of software.
They're very comfortable with modern
software.
China is not one giant economic country.
It's got many provinces and cities with
mayors all competing with each other.
That's the reason why there's so many EV
companies. That's the reason why there's
so many AI companies. That's the reason
why there's so many every company you
could imagine. Um they all create some
of them and and um as a result they have
insane competition internally and you
know what remains is an incredible
company. Um they also have a um social
culture where where it's family first,
friends second and company third.
And so
um
the amount of conversation that goes
back and forth between they're
essentially open source all the time. So
the fact that they contribute more to
open source is so sensible because
they're probably what are we protecting?
You know my engineers their brothers are
in that company their friends are in
that company and they're all
schoolmates. you know the schoolmate
concept it's a you know one schoolmate
your brother for life and um and so they
they they share knowledge very very
quickly and so there's no sense keeping
technology hidden you might as well put
it on open source and so the open source
community then amplifies accelerates the
the innovation process so you get this
rapid incredibly great talent rapid
innovation because of open source and
just you the the nature of friends and
and um insane competition among compet
among the company what emerges is
incredible stuff and so this is the
fastest innovating
country in the world today and this is
something that has everything that
everything that I've just said is
fundamental to just how the kids were
grown the fact that they have excellent
education the fact that they parents
want them to do well in school the fact
that they their culture that way. These
are, you know, these are just the thing
about their country and they showed up
at a precisely the time when technology
is going through that exponential.
>> Plus, culturally, it's pretty cool to be
an engineer. It connects to all the
components that you're mentioning.
>> It's a it's a builder nation.
>> It's a builder nation.
>> Yeah, it's a builder nation. Um, our
country's leaders, incredible, but
they're mostly lawyers. They're
country's leaders and because we're
they're trying to keep us safe. uh rule
of law, uh governing. Their country was
built out of poverty and so most of
their leaders are incredible engineers,
some of the brightest minds.
To take a small tangent because you
mentioned open source, I have to uh go
to Perplexity here, who you have been a
a fan of a long time.
>> I love it. Yeah.
>> And thank you for releasing open source
Neatron 3 Super, which you can also use
inside Perplexity. look stuff up.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh which is uh 120 billion parameter
open weight uh model.
>> Uh what's your vision
with open source? So you mentioned China
with with Deep Seek with Minia with all
these companies really pushing forward
the open- source uh AI movement and
Nvidia is really leading the way in um
close to state-of-the-art open source
LMS. What's your vision there?
>> First,
if we're going to be a great AI
computing company, we have to understand
how AI models are evolving.
>> One of the things that I love about
Neotron 3 is it's it's not a just a pure
transformer model. It's transformer and
SSM. And uh we were early in uh
developing the the uh conditional GANs
which that progressive GANs which led
step by step to diffusion. And so um the
fact that we're doing basic research in
model architecture and in different
domains gives us visibility into you
know what kind of computing systems
would do a good job for future models
and so it is part of our extreme
codeesign strategy. Second,
um I think we we right rightfully
recognize that on the one hand we want
worldclass models as products and they
should be proprietary.
On the other hand, we also want AI to
diffuse into every industry and every
country, every researcher, every
student.
And if everything is proprietary, it's
hard to do research and it's hard to
innovate on top of around with. And so
open source is fundamentally necessary
for many industries to join the AI
revolution.
Nvidia has the scale and we have the
motives to not only skills, scale and
motivation to build and continue to
build these AI models for as long as we
shall live. And so therefore, we ought
to do that. We can open up, we can
activate every industry, every
researcher, you know, every country to
be able to join the AI revolution.
There's a third reason which is for that
to recognizing that AI is not just
language. These AIs will likely use uh
tools and models and sub aents that were
trained on other modalities of
information. Maybe it's biology or
chemistry or um you know laws of physics
or you know fluids and thermodynamics
and not all of it is in language
structure. And so somebody has to go
make sure that weather prediction,
biology, AI, AI for biology, physical
AI, all of that stuff stays can be
pushed to the limits and pushed to the
frontier. We don't build cars, but we
want to make sure every car company has
access to great models. We don't we
don't discover drugs, but I want to make
sure that Lily has the world's best
biology AI systems so that they can go
use it for discovering drugs. And so
these three fundamental reasons both in
in recognizing that AI is not just the
language that AI is really broad that we
want to engage everybody into the world
of AI and then also codees of AI.
>> Well, I have to say once again, thank
you uh for open sourcing really truly
open sourcing uh Neatron 3. And
>> yeah, I appreciate you were saying that
we open source the models, we open
source the weights, we open source the
data, we open source how we created it.
>> Yeah, it's pretty amazing.
It's really It's really incredible.
You're originally from Taiwan and have a
close relationship with TSMC. So I have
to ask uh TSMC I think uh also is a
legendary company in terms of the
engineering teams in terms of the
incredible engineering work that they
do. uh what [snorts]
uh what do you understand about TSMC
culture and their approach that explains
how they're able to achieve this
singular unmatched success in uh
everything they're doing with
semiconductors? You know, first of all,
the deepest misunderstanding about TSMC
is that that um
their technology
is all they have. that somehow they they
have a really great transistor and if
somebody shows up another transistor
game over
>> it's the technology and of course you
know I I don't mean just the trans
transistor the metalization systems the
packaging the 3D packaging the silicon
photonics the you know all of the
technology that they have that
technology is really what makes the
company special their technology makes
the company special
but their ability to orchestrate
the the demands the the dynamic demands
of hundreds of companies in the world as
they're moving up, shifting out, you
know, increasing, decreasing, push
pushing out, pulling in, um changing
from customer to customer, uh wafer
starting, wafer stopping,
uh emergency wafer starts, you know, all
of this dynamics of the world's
complexity as the world is shapeshifting
all the time and somehow they're running
a factory with high throughput, high
yields, really great costs, excellent
customer service. They they take their
work ser they take their promises
seriously. when your wafer because they
know that you're help they're helping
you run your company when the wafers
when the wafers were promised to show up
the wafers show up you know so that you
could run your company appropriately and
so their system their manufacturing
system is completely miraculous I would
say then the second thing is their
culture this culture is uh
simultaneously
uh technology focused on one hand
advancing technology
simultaneously customer serviceoriented
on the other hand a lot of
C companies are very customer
serviceoriented, but they're not very
technology
excellent. They're they're not at the
bleeding edge of technology or a lot of
companies who are tech at the bleeding
edge of technology, but they're not the
best customer service oriented company.
And so it just depends on somehow
they've they've balanced these two and
they're world class at both. Um and then
probably the third thing is the
technology that I most value in them uh
that they created this you know this
this uh intangible called trust. I trust
them to put my company on top of them.
That's a very big deal. But they trust I
mean there's a really close relationship
there that you've established and that
trust is established based on many years
of performance. But there's human
relationships involved there as well.
three decades. I don't know how many
tens, hundreds of billions of dollars of
business we've done through them and we
don't have a contract.
That's pretty great. Amazing. Okay.
There's a story uh that in 2013 the
founders of TSMC, Morris Jang, offered
you the chance to become TSMC's chief
executive.
Uh and you said you already had a job.
Is this story true?
>> Story is true. I didn't I didn't dismiss
it. Yeah. Um uh but I was I was deeply
honored and and of course of course um
uh I knew then as I know now TSMC is one
of the most consequential companies in
history.
>> Yeah. And and Morris is one of the the
highest regarded executive and and um
business and personal friend that I've
that I've had in my life. And um
uh for him to ask is uh uh um I I was
humbled and and really honored.
Um but but the work that I'm doing here
is really important and I've seen you
know in my mind anyways in my mind's eye
what Nvidia was going to be and what the
impact that we could have and um uh it
was really important work
and it's my responsibility you know my
sole responsibility to make this happen
and so I I um uh I declined it you know
[clears throat]
not not because it wasn't an incredible
offer Uh it it's an unbelievable offer.
Um but but I simply couldn't take it.
>> I think Nvidia, both Nvidia and TSMC are
two of the greatest companies in the
history of human civilization. Running
either one, I'm sure, is incredibly
complicated effort and it takes you have
to truly be allin.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh everybody at every scale, not just at
the CEO level, everybody is really truly
allin.
>> Yeah.
>> To accomplish this kind of complexity.
>> See, now I can help both companies.
>> Exactly. [laughter] Um, so Nvidia is now
the most valuable company in the world.
I have to ask, what is the Nvidia's
biggest moat as the folks in the tech
sector say?
>> Mhm.
>> The edge you have that protects you from
the competition.
Our single
most important uh property as a company
is the install base of our computing
platform. Our single most important
thing is the invol today is our is the
installed base of CUDA. Now the reason
why uh
20 20 years ago of course there was no
installed base but what makes and if
somebody if somebody came up with with a
guda [clears throat] or a tuda uh it
wouldn't make any difference at all. And
the reason for that is because because
it's never been just about the
technology. The technology of course was
incredible visionary. Um but it's the
fact that the company was dedicated to
it, stuck with it, expanded its reach.
Um it wasn't three people that that made
CUDA successful. It was 43,000 people
that made CUDA successful. and the
several million developers that believed
in us um that trusted that we were going
to continue to make CUDA 1 2 3 13 that
they decided to port and dedicate their
software on top of it, their mountain of
software on top of it. And so the
install base is the number one most
important advantage. that installed base
when you amplified with the velocity of
our execution at the scale that we're
talking about. No company in history had
ever built systems of this complexity
period. And then to build it once a year
is impossible.
And and
that velocity combined with the
installed base in the developer's mind
is just going to now take the
developer's mind. From the developers
perspective, if I support CUDA
tomorrow, it will be 10 times better. I
just have to wait 6 months on average.
Not only that, if I develop it on CUDA,
I reach a few hundred million people
computers. I'm in every cloud. I'm in
every computer company. I'm in every
single industry. I'm in every single
country.
So if I created an open source package
and I put it on CUDA first,
I get these both attributes
simultaneously.
And not only that,
I trust 100%
that Nvidia is going to keep CUDA around
and maintain it and improve it and keep
optimizing the libraries for as long as
they shall live.
You could take that to the bank. And
that last part, trust,
you put all that stuff together, if I
were a developer today, I would target
CUDA first. I would target CUDA most.
And that's the reason that that I think
in the final analysis is our first
that's even our first
>> core advantage. Our second one is our
ecosystem.
>> The fact that we vertically integrated
this incredibly complex system, but we
integrated horizontally into every
single every single company's computers.
We're in the Google cloud, we're in
Amazon, we're in Azure.
>> You know, we're ramping up AWS like
crazy right now. We're in new companies
like Corewave and Nscale. We're in
supercomputers at Lily. We're in
enterprise computers. We're at the edge
in radio base stations. You know, I it's
just crazy. One architecture is in all
these different systems. We're in cars,
we're in robots, we're in satellites,
we're out in space. And so, so the fact
that you have this one architecture and
the ecosystem is so broad, it basically
covers every single industry in the
world. Well, how does the how does the
CUDA install base evolve into the future
with AI factories as a moat? What do you
what do do you think it's possible that
Nvidia of the future is all about the AI
factory? Well, the the unit of computing
used to be GPU to us, then it became a
computer. Then it became a cluster. Now
it's an entire AI factory. when I see a
computer, when I see what Nvidia builds
in the old days, I would, you know, I
visualize the chip
>> and then and then when I announced a new
product, you know, new generation, like
ladies and gentlemen, we're announcing
ampear today. I pick up the chip.
>> Yeah.
>> That was my mental model what I was
building.
>> Today, I don't I wouldn't picking up the
chip is kind of still adorable,
>> but it's adorable. It It's not It's not
my mental model of what I'm doing. My
mental model is this giant gigawatt
thing that has power generation. It's
connected to the grid. It's got cooling
systems and networking of incredible
monstrosity. You know, 10,000 people are
in there trying to install it. Hundreds
of networking engineers in there.
Thousands of engineers behind it trying
to power it up.
>> You know, powering up one of those
factories, as you know, it's not
somebody going, "It's on now."
[laughter]
takes thousands of people to bring it
up.
>> So mentally you're actually when you're
thinking about a single unit of compute,
you're like literally when you go to bed
at night, you're thinking now about
collection of racks. So pods, not
individual chips,
>> entire infrastructure. And I'm hoping my
next click is when I'm thinking about
building computers, it's, you know,
planetary scale. That would be the next
click. What do you think about the space
angle that Elon has talked about doing
compute in space uh for solving some of
the it makes some of the energy issues
in terms of scaling energy easier
cooling issues is not easy. Yeah,
>> cooling well there's a large number of
engineering complexities involved with
that.
>> So what you know Nvidia has also
announced that
>> you're already thinking about that.
>> Yeah, we're already there. Uh, Nvidia
GPUs are the first GPUs in space and um
I I didn't realize it was it was so
interesting to I would have declared it
maybe we're in space, you know, little
little astronaut suit on one of our
GPUs. [laughter]
Um but but we've been in space. Uh it's
the right place to do a lot of imaging.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, because those satellites have
really high resolution imaging systems
and they're sweeping the Earth, you
know, continuously now. And um uh you
want you know centimeter scale you know
imaging that is done continuously uh for
the world so that you know you'll
basically have real time telemetry of
everything. Uh you don't want to beam
that back down to earth. It's just you
know pabytes and pabytes of data. You
got to just do AI right there at the
edge. Throw away everything you don't
need. You've seen before didn't change
and then just keep the stuff that that
you need. And so AI ought to be done at
the edge. Um obviously we have we have
uh 24/7 solar if we put it at the polars
and um uh
but you know there's no conduction, no
convection and so you know you're pretty
much just radiation
and um uh but you know space is big I
guess. You know we're just going to put
big giant radiators out there.
>> How crazy of an idea do you think it is?
Like is this is this 5 years out, 10
years out, 20 years out? [gasps] So, uh,
we're talking about blockers for AI
scaling. You know, I'm just so much more
practical. I I look for where where um I
next next bucket of opportunities are
first.
Meanwhile, I'm cultivating space. And
so, I send I send engineers uh to go
work on the problem. We're we're
starting to we're learning a lot about
it. Um, how do we deal with radiation?
How do we deal with degrading
performance? How do we deal with um uh
continuous uh testing and addestation of
of um def defects and and um you know
how do we deal with redundancy and how
do we degrade uh gracefully and things
like that and so we could we could do uh
what what about software? How do you
think about software and and redundancy
and performance out in space? Uh make it
so that so that the computer never
breaks. It just gets slower, you know.
And um I so we could start doing a lot
of engineer exploration up front, but in
the meantime, my my favorite answer is
get eliminate waste.
>> You know, we've we've got all that idle
power. I want to evacuate it as fast as
possible. [laughter]
>> Yeah. There Yeah, there's a lot of low
hanging fruit here on Earth uh that we
can utilize uh for the AI scaling. Uh
quick pause, quick 30 second thank you
to our sponsors. Check them out in the
description. It really is the best way
to support this podcast. Go to
lexfreedman.com/sponsors.
We got Perplexity for curiositydriven
knowledge exploration, Shopify for
selling stuff online, Element for
Electrolytes, Finn for customer service
AI agents, and Quo for a phone system
like calls, texts, contacts for your
business. Choose wisely, my friends. And
now back to my conversation with Johnson
Kuang. Do you think Nvidia may be worth
10 trillion at some point? Let's let's
ask it this way. What does the future of
the world look like where that where
that's true?
I think that Nvidia's growth is is um
uh extremely likely and in my mind
inevitable. And let me explain why.
[gasps] We're the largest computer
company in history.
That alone should beg the question why.
And the reason for of course uh two
reasons. First two foundational
technical reasons. The first reason is
that computing went from being a
retrievalbased file retrieval system.
Almost everything is a file. We we pre
pre-write something, we pre-record
something, you know, we we draw
something, we put it on the web, we put
in a file, and we we use a recommener
system, some smart filter to figure out
what to retrieve for you. And so we were
a pre-recording, human pre-recording and
file retrieving system. That's what a
computer is largely
to now AI computers are contextually
aware which means that it has to process
and generate tokens in real time. So we
went from a retrievalbased computing
system to a generativebased computing
system.
We're going to need a lot more
processing in this new world than in the
old world. We need a lot of storage in
the old old world. We need a lot of
computation in this new world. And so so
that's that's the first part of it. We
fundamentally changed computing and the
way how computing is done. The only
thing that would cause it to go back is
if this way of computation, this way of
computing generating information that's
contextually relevant, situationally
aware that is grounded on new insight
before it generates information. this
computationintensive way of doing
computing would only go back if it's not
effective. So if for the last 1015 years
while working on deep learning if at any
single moment
I would have come to the conclusion that
that you know what this is not going to
work out I think this is a dead end or
it's not going to scale it's not going
to solve this modality it's not going to
be used in this application then of
course I would feel very differently
about it but I think the last five years
has given me more confidence than the
last 10 years the previous 10 years the
second idea
is computers because it was a storage
system. It was largely a warehouse.
We're now building factories.
Warehouses don't make much money.
Factories directly correlates with a
company's revenues.
And so
the computer did two things. Not only
did it change the way it did it, its
purpose in the world changed. It's no
longer a computer, it's a factory. It's
a factory is used for generation of
revenues.
We're now seeing not only is this
factory generating products, commodities
that people want to consume,
we're seeing that the commodities are so
interesting, so valuable so to so many
different audiences that the tokens are
starting to segment like iPhones.
>> Mhm.
>> You have a free tokens, you have premium
tokens, and you have several tokens in
the middle. And so intelligence, as it
turns out, you know, is a scalable
product. There's extremely high
intelligence products, tokens that you
could that are used for specialized
things. People be willing to pay, you
know, the idea that somebody's willing
to pay $1,000 per million tokens is just
around the corner. It's not if, it's
only when. And so so now we're seeing
that the commodity that this factory
makes is actually valuable and is
revenue generating and profit
generating. How now the question is how
many of these factories can does the
world need?
How much how many tokens does the world
need?
And um
how much is society willing to pay for
these tokens?
And
what would happen to the world's economy
if the productivity were to improve so
substantially?
What would happen? Are we are we going
to discover new drugs, new products, new
services? And so when you take these
things in combination, I am absolutely
certain
that the world's GDP is going to
accelerate in growth. I'm absolutely
certain the percentage of that GDP that
will be used for computation
will be a 100 times more than the past
because it's no longer a storage unit.
It's a product generation unit. And so
when you look at it in that context and
then you back into what is Nvidia's what
does Nvidia what does Nvidia do and how
much of that
new economics new industry would we have
to benefit to address I think we're
going to be a lot lot bigger and then
the rest of it to me is um you go is it
possible for Nvidia to be a you know $3
trillion revenues company in the near
future
The answer is of course yes. And the
reason for that is because it's not
limited by any physical limits. There's
nothing that I see that says, you know,
gosh, um, $3 trillion is not possible.
And as it turns out, Nvidia supply chain
is the burden is shared by 200
companies.
and the fact that we scale out on the
backs of with the partnership of this
ecosystem.
The question is do we have the energy to
do so? And surely we will have the
energy to do so. And so all of these
things combined
that number is just a number you know
and I still remember Nvidia was a Nvidia
was a the first time we crossed a
billion dollars.
I was reminded of of a CEO who told me,
you know, Jensen, it's theoretically
impossible for a fabulous semiconductor
company to exceed a billion dollars. And
and um I won't bore you with why, but
but the of course is illogical and
there's a lot of evidence we're not. And
then there somebody told me, you know,
Jensen, you'll never be more than $25
billion because of some other company.
Somebody told me that you'll never be,
you know, because and then so so the the
those aren't principled first principle
reason thinking and the simple the
simple way to think about that is what
is it that we make and how large is the
opportunity that we can create. Now
Nvidia is not in the market share
business. Almost everything that I just
talked about don't exist.
>> Mhm.
>> That's the part that's hard.
You know, if Nvidia was a was a was a
$10 billion company trying to take
Nvidia's share, then it's easy to to see
for shareholders that oh yeah, if they
could just take 10% share, they could be
this much larger. But it's hard for
people to imagine how large we could be
because there's nobody I could take
share from,
>> you know, and so so I think that that's
one of the challenges for the world is
is um the imagination of the future. But
I got plenty of time and I'll keep
reasoning about it and I'll keep talking
about it and every single GTC will
become more and more real,
>> you know, and and and then more and more
people will talk about one of these
days, you know, we'll we'll get there.
But I'm 100% we'll get there.
>> Yeah. this view of uh you know token
factories essentially this token per
second per watt and every token having
value like it's an actual thing that
brings value and it brings different
kinds of value different amounts of
value to different people but it's value
that's the actual product is really
could be loosely thought of as the token
and so you have a bunch of token factors
and it's very easy first principles to
imagine a future given all the potential
things that AI can solve that you're
going to need an exponential number more
of token factories.
>> Yeah.
>> And and what's really interesting, the
reason why I was so excited about it,
the iPhone of tokens arrived.
>> What do you call Wait, are you saying
open clause iPhone?
>> Yeah,
>> that's interesting. Uh
>> agents.
>> Yeah, agents. True.
>> Agents in general. [laughter] The iPhone
of tokens arrived. Uh it is the fastest
growing application in history. It went
straight up.
>> Yeah,
>> went straight up.
>> That says something.
>> Yep. There's no question OpenClaw is the
iPhone of tokens. Yeah, there's
something truly as you know
something truly special happening from
about December where people really woke
up to the power of claw code of codeex
of open claw. Um, I mean, I've
embarrassed to admit that on the way
here in the airport,
I've
this first time I've done this in
public, I was programming quote unquote
by talking to my laptop [laughter] and I
was embarrassed because I was pretending
like I'm talking to a human colleague.
Mhm.
>> Uh I'm not sure how I feel about the
future where everybody
>> is walking around talking to their AI,
but it's such an efficient way to get
stuff done
>> and and it's it's more likely that your
AI is bothering you all the time. And
the reason for that is because it's
getting stuff done so fast.
>> Yeah.
>> Is reporting back to you. I got that
done. You know, what do you want me to
do next? You know, it that's the part
that I think most people don't realize
is mo the person who's going to be
chatting with them, texting them most is
their is their claws or lobster.
[laughter]
>> What an incredible future. Uh I read
that you attribute a lot of your success
to your ability to work harder than
anyone and withstand more suffering than
anyone.
So, we can list many of the things that
entails. I mean, dealing with failure,
the constant engineering problems we've
talked about, the the human problems,
uncertainty, responsibility, exhaustion,
embarrassment, the near-death company
moments that you've mentioned,
um, but also the pressure now as the CEO
of this
company that economies and nations
strategize around, uh, plan their, um,
financial allocations around plan their
in AI infrastructure around how do you
deal with this much pressure?
What gives you strength given
how many nations and peoples depend on
you?
I'm conscious about the fact that
um Nvidia success is very important to
United States.
We generate enormous amounts of tax tax
revenues. Uh we establish technology
leadership for our nation. Technology
leadership is important for national
security. National security not just in
one aspect of national security. All
aspects of national security. When our
country is more prosperous,
we could do a better job with domestic
policies and helping social social
benefits because we're generating so
much re-industrialization in the United
States. We're creating mountains of
jobs. We're helping shift um how we how
we how we build things uh back to United
States in so many different plants,
chips, computers, and of course these AI
factories. I'm completely aware that
that um and I have I have the benefit
and this is a real real um a real gift
uh with with uh mainstream investors,
teachers, policemen who have somehow for
whatever reason invested in Nvidia or
because they watch Jim Kramer um bought
some stock and now are millionaires.
>> Mhm. And um I I am completely aware of
that circumstance. I'm aware of the
circumstance that that Nvidia
uh
is central to a very large network of
ecosystem partners behind us and
downstream from us. And so the way the
way I deal with that is exactly what I
just did. I reason about
what is it what is it that we're doing?
um what is it causing? What's the impact
that has other people benefit you know
positively or even even um uh through
great burden for example the supply
chain
and and the question is
uh therefore what are you going to do
about it and almost everything that I
feel I break it down I reason about okay
what's the circumstance what is what has
changed what's hard um and what am I
going to do about it and I I break it
down, decompose the problem. And the de
the decomposition
of these
circumstances
turns it into manageable things that I
can do. And the only thing that I after
that I could do is did you do it? Did
you either do it or did you get somebody
else to do it? And if you didn't do it,
you you reason that you need to do it
and you didn't do it and you get didn't
get anybody else to do it, then stop
crying about it, you know. And so, and
so, so I I'm I'm fairly I'm fairly uh
>> uh tough on myself. And but I also break
things down so that so that um uh I
don't panic. Uh I can go to sleep
because I've made the list of things
that needed to be done. And I've made
sure that everything that could put our
company in harm's way, could put my
partners in harm's way, put our industry
in harm's way, I've told somebody.
Everything that I feel could put anybody
in harm's way, I've told someone. And
I've told that someone who could do
something about it. And so I've gotten
it off my chest or I'm doing something
about it. And so after that, Lex, what
else can you do?
>> So given all the in insane intense
amount of suffering on the journey of
building up Nvidia,
you have you hit low points
psychologically?
>> Oh yeah. Oh yeah, sure. All the time.
All the time.
>> And there you just break down the
problem
>> into pieces.
>> Yeah.
>> See what you can do about it.
>> And and part of And you know, Lex, part
of it part of it is forgetting. One of
the most important attributes of AI
learning as you know is right systematic
forgetting. You you need to know when to
forget some things. You can't memorize
everything. You can't keep everything.
and and you know you want to you don't
want to carry everything. One of the
things that I do very quickly is I
decompose the problem. I reason about
the problem and I I share the load with
it. When I say I tell everybody, I'm
essentially sharing that burden.
>> Yeah.
>> As quickly as possible.
Whatever worries me, tell somebody else.
Don't just keep it, you know, decompo.
Don't don't freak them out. decompose
the problem into smaller parts and get
people to so and and inspire them to be
able to go do something about it. But
part of it is just just forgetting, you
know, I a lot of it is you got to be
tough on yourself, you know, just come
on, stop crying about it, let's get
going, you know, and and then you get
out of bed. And then the other part is
is um you you you're attracted to the
next shiny light, the next future, you
know, the next opportunity, the next
Okay, that's behind us. Let what's next?
It's a lot. I think you know you watch
this with great athletes. They they um
just worry about the next point.
>> Mhm.
>> The last point is behind them. The
embarrassment,
the you know, the [laughter] setback,
you know, and and then and because I do
so much of my job publicly,
>> you know, Lex, you do a fair amount of
your job publicly, too. And so, so I do
a lot of my job publicly. And so, um,
you know, I I say a lot of things that
that seem sensible at the time or funny
at the time. Mostly it's just because
it's funny to me at the time and then,
you know, you reflect on it's less
money, but but
>> Yeah. No, trust me, I know. But you
basically allow yourself to be pulled by
the light of the future. Forget the past
and just keep
>> That's right.
>> Keep keep working towards that. I mean,
you did say there's this kind of famous
thing you said that um if you knew how
hard it would be to build Nvidia, uh it
turned out to be what is it a million
times more hard than you anticipated
that you wouldn't do it?
>> Yeah.
>> But is isn't you know when I hear that
that's probably true about everything
worth doing, right?
>> Exactly. That is by the way what I was
trying to explain is that there's a
there's a incredible superpower of being
um being being uh have the mind of a
child.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and I say to myself often
times when I look at something and and
almost almost everything
um my first thought is how hard can it
be? [laughter]
>> You know, and so and so you get yourself
into that mode. How hard could it be?
and and nobody's ever done it. It looks
gigantic. It's going to cost hundreds of
billions of dollars. It's going to take,
you know, all this. And you just go,
"Yeah, but how hard could it be?" You
know, how hard could it be?
>> And and so, so you got to get yourself
into that state of mind. You don't want
to you don't want to actually
overstimulate
everything and all the setbacks and all
the trials and tribulations and all the
disappointments. You don't want to
simulate all that in advance. You don't
want to know that. You don't you don't
you want to go into a new experience
thinking it's going to be perfect. It's
going to be great. It's going to be
incredibly fun. And then while you're
there, you know, you need to have you
need to have endurance. You need to have
grit so that when the setbacks actually
happened and those setbacks are going to
surprise you, the disappoints
disappointments aren't going to surprise
you. You know, the embarrassments are
going to surprise you, the humiliations
are going to surprise you. Um you just
can't let now you just got to turn on
the other bit which is just forget about
it. move on, keep keep moving. And and
to the extent that
to the extent that my assumptions
about the future and why the future is
going to manifest,
so long as those assumptions and that
input
doesn't change or didn't change
materially, then I should expect that
the output won't change. And so my
simulated output of the future is still
going to happen. And if it's still going
to happen, I'm still going to go after
it. I believe it's going to, you know,
and so there's a combination of two or
three human characteristics.
The ability to go into a into an
experience fresh-minded,
the ability to forget the setbacks,
the ability to believe in yourself,
you know, to believe what you believe
and stay stay true to that belief. Um,
but you're constantly re-evaluating.
>> Mhm. This combination of three, four,
five things I think is is really
important for resilience. And and um
and you know, I I'm I'm fortunate that
that whatever whatever life experience
has led to this, I've got kind of those
four or five things. You know, I'm
always curious, always learning. I'm
always learning from everybody. You
know, I'm always asking my and because
I'm humble about about about everything,
I'm always thinking, gosh, they did that
so nicely. They did that so wonderfully.
You know, I wonder what they're thinking
through. How do they, you know, so I'm
simulating everybody in a lot of ways,
you know, I'm emulating almost everybody
I watch, right? you're you're empathetic
towards towards everything that they do
that that you're observing and respect
and and so you you're constantly
learning and you know
>> you're now one of the wealthiest people
on earth, one of the most successful
humans on earth. Is it harder to be
humble and to be able to do you feel the
effect of money and power and fame in
making it harder for you to
sort of be wrong in your own head enough
to
hear out an opinion of somebody else
when it disagrees with you and learn
from them? Those kinds of things.
>> Um, surprisingly, no. And and I would I
would actually go the other way because
I do so much of my work publicly.
When I'm wrong, pretty much everybody
sees it. [laughter]
>> You get humbled.
>> Yeah. And and uh and when I'm wrong,
when I'm wrong or it didn't turn out
that way or um you know, I mean, most of
the things that that I say outside um
I'm fairly certain about. And the reason
for that is because because it's going
to impact somebody else and I want to be
quite concerned about that and quite
quite circumspect about that. Um for
stuff that that I'm reasoning about
inside a meeting, you know, a lot of
things could turn out differently. And
so, but it doesn't ever stop me from
reasoning. The way that that the way
that I manage and lead, I you know, I'm
constantly reasoning in front of people.
Even when I'm talking to you, you can
kind of see me kind of reasoning through
things.
>> And I want to make sure that you
understand what I'm saying, not because
I told you,
>> because I'm so humble about what I'm
about to tell you.
>> I kind of show you the steps that I got
there.
>> And then you could decide whether you
believe what I said in the end. And so
I'm doing that all day long in meetings
with all of my employees. I'm constantly
reasoning through. Let me tell you, let
me tell you what how I see it. And I
reason through it. It gives everybody
the opportunity to intercept and say, "I
disagree with that part."
>> The nice thing about reasoning through
things and letting and letting people
interact with it is that they don't have
to disagree with your outcome.
They can disagree with your reasoning
steps and they could pull me in
different directions and then we can
reason forward. And so we're we're kind
of, you know, collective
patharching method and it's really
fantastic.
>> Yeah. You have this way about you of
when you're explaining stuff, I can feel
you actually reasoning on the spot about
it with a constant open-mindedness where
you could I I could feel like I could
steer your thinking. Yeah. And that's a
that's really beautiful that you've been
able to maintain that after so many
years of success and pain. I think
sometimes pain makes you close you down
a bit.
>> Yeah.
>> And I I think to maintain
>> tolerance for embarrassment I think is
[laughter]
>> that's that's the tolerance. I mean
that's a real thing.
>> Yeah. There's many years of embarrassing
yourself. Even those meetings knowing
that there's people around you where you
declared one idea and it was shown that
that idea was wrong and be able to admit
that and to grow from that. That's not
that's very difficult on a human level.
>> Yeah. Well, you know, they knew I was
they knew that recently my first job was
was, you know, cleaning toilets. So,
>> I'm glad you maintain that same spirit
of Denny's um the the work. I mean, that
that was beautiful. your whole journey
from starting from Denny's is a
beautiful one. Uh let me ask you about
video games. So I'm a big gaming fan.
>> Yeah.
>> So I have to say thank you to Nvidia for
many years of incredible graphics.
Um
>> by the way it it is GeForce is our still
to this day.
>> Yeah.
>> Our number one marketing strategy.
Right. People learn about Nvidia while
they're in their teenage years.
>> Mhm. And then they go to college and
they know who Nvidia is and they and
then in the beginning it's just you know
playing Call of Duty you know you know
Fortnite and then later they're using
CUDA and then later they're using Nvidia
and you know Blender and Do and Auto.
>> I mean I should say I I mentioned to a
friend that I'm uh talking with you. He
said oh they make [laughter]
great gaming GPUs.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. you know,
there's there's [laughter] more to it,
but but yeah. Yeah, people really love
the it really brought a lot of joy to a
lot of people. The the the hardware
really brings these worlds to life.
>> Uh there was some controversy around
this uh with DLSS 5. Yeah.
>> Can you explain to me the drama around
this? Uh I guess people gamers online
were concerned that it makes games look
like AI slop.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh what do you think of this drama?
Yeah, I think their their perspective
makes sense and I could see where
they're coming from because I don't love
AI slob myself. You know, all of the the
AI generated content increasingly
um looks similar and they're all
beautiful and and I can so I can I'm
empathetic towards what they're what
they're thinking. Um that's just not
what DLSS 5 is trying to do. I showed
several examples of it, but DLSS5
is 3D conditioned, 3D guided. It's
ground truth structure data guided. And
so, so the artist determine the
geometry. We are completely truthful
to the geometry maintain so in every
single frame. Um it's uh conditioned by
the textures, the artistry of the
artist. And so every single frame it
enhances but it doesn't change anything.
Now the question is the question about
enhancing.
DLSS5 also lets because it's the system
is open you could train your own models
to determine and you could even in the
future prompt it you know I want it to
be a toune shader. I want it to look
like this kind of, you know, so you can
give it even an example and it would
generate in the style of that all
consistent with the artistry, you know,
the style, the intent of the artist. And
so all of that is done for the artist so
that they can create something that is
more beautiful um but still in the style
that they want.
I think that they got the impression
that the the games are going to come out
the way the games are shipped the way
they do and then we're going to
post-process it. That's not what DLSS is
intended to do. DLSS is integrated with
the artist. And so it's it's about
giving the artist the tool of AI, the
tool of generative AI. They could decide
not to use it. You know,
>> I think people are very sensitive to
human faces.
>> Yeah. And we're now living in this
moment, which I think is a is a
beautiful one, which is people are
sensitive to AI slop.
>> Yeah.
>> It it puts a mirror to ourselves to help
us realize that what we seek as
imperfections, what we seek is sometimes
not perfect graphics, it helps us
understand what we find compelling in
the worlds we create.
>> And that's beautiful. And as long as
it's tools that help us create those
worlds.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> It's it's wonderful.
>> That's right. It's yet another tool. and
they want the generative uh models to
generate the opposite of photoreal.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. It'll do that too. And so it's
just yet another tool. I think the um
the gamers might might also appreciate
that that um in the last couple years we
we introduced
uh skin shaders
to the game developers and many of those
games have skin shaders that include
subs subsurface scattering that make
skin look more skin-like. And so the
industry's game developers are looking
for more and more and more tools to
express their art. And so this is just
yet more one more tool they could decide
what to use.
>> Ridiculous question. Uh what do you
think is the greatest or most
influential game ever made? Maybe from
Nvidia's perspective.
>> Doom.
>> Doom. Unquestionably. That was the start
of the 3D. I would say Doom from a from
a the intersection of the cultural
implication as well as the industry
turning a PC into a gaming device. That
was a very important moment. Now, of
course, flight simulation companies were
before it
>> and um but they just didn't have the
popularity that Doom did to have made
the industry turned the PC from a office
automation tool into a personal computer
for families and gamers and things like
that. And so Doom was really impactful
there. From a from an actual game
technology perspective, I would say
Virtual Fighter. And so we we're great
friends with both of them, you know. And
then there's games more recently. I
mean, Cyberpunk 2077,
really nice GPU,
accelerated graphics, like fully ray
traced,
>> fully ray traced. Um, also I like I
personally I'm a huge fan of Skyrim, uh,
Elder Scrolls and the, you know, it's
been released a long long time ago, but
people release mods and they
I mean it it's like a different game and
it just allows me to replay the game
over and over and it get it makes you
realize you can reexperience in a
totally new way the world you already
love.
>> So I I do that all the time. One of my
favorite [laughter] games just walk
around Skyrim. We created this thing
called RTX Mod.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. It's a modding tool.
>> Awesome.
>> And allows it allows the community to
inject the latest technology into an old
game.
>> Of course, like what makes a great video
game is not just graphics. It's also
story and character development. But
that's right. Beautiful graphics can add
to the the immersion, the the feeling
like it's another place you're
transported to.
uh what's uh you said I think accurately
that the AGI timeline
question rests on your definition of
AGI.
So let let's let me ask you about a
possible timelines here. Let's this
ridiculous definition perhaps of what
AGI is but a an AI system that's able to
essentially do your job. So run, no
start,
grow and run a successful technology
company that's worth
>> a good one or A1.
>> No, it has [laughter] to it has to be
worth more than a billion
more more than a billion dollars.
So you know, you know how hard it is to
do all those components. So how far are
we away from that? So we're talking
about open claw that does all the
incredibly complex stuff that are
required to to first of all innovate to
find customers to sell to them to to
manage to build a team of some agents
some humans all that kind of stuff. Is
this 5 10 15 20 years away?
>> I think it's now I think we've achieved
AGI.
>> You think you can have a company run by
an AI system like this?
>> Possible. And the reason for that is
this. You said a billion and you didn't
say forever and and so for example uh it
is not out of the question that
uh a claw was able to create a web
service some interesting little app that
all of a sudden you know a few billion
people used for 50 and then it went out
of business again shortly after. Now, we
saw a whole bunch of those type of
companies during the internet era and
most of the those websites were not
anything more sophisticated than what
Open Claw could generate today.
>> Interesting. Achieve virality and
monetize that virality.
>> Yeah. It's just that I don't know what
it is, but I I couldn't have predicted
any of those companies at the time
either. You know,
>> you're going to get a lot of people
excited with that statement.
>> Yeah. It's like, what do you mean? I can
I can just uh launch an agent and u make
a lot of money? Well, by the way, it's
happening right now, right? You know
that when when you go to China, uh
you're going to see you're going to see
um a whole bunch of people uh teaching
their getting their claws to try to go
out and look for jobs and, you know, do
work, make money. And and I'm not I'm
not actually I wouldn't be surprised if
some social thing happened or somebody
created a a digital influencer, super
super cute. um or some social
application that you know feeds your
little tomagotchi or something like that
and and it become an out of the blue an
instant success. A lot of people use it
for a couple of months and it kind of
dies away. Now the odds of of of
you know 100,000 of those agents um
building Nvidia 0%.
And and then and then the the one part
that I will I will do um and I and I I
want to make sure we all do is to
recognize that people are really worried
about their jobs
and and um I just want to remind them
that the purpose of your job and the
tasks and the tools that you use to do
your job are related, not the same. I've
been doing my job for 33 years. I'm the
longest running tech CEO in the world.
34 years and the tools that I've used to
do my job has changed
continuously in the last 34 years and
sometimes quite dramatically you know
over the course of a couple two three
years and and the the the one story that
I I I really want to make sure that
everybody hears is the story the the
first job that every that computer
scientists said AI researchers said was
going to go away was radiology
because computer vision was going to
achieve superhuman levels and it did. CV
computer vision was superhuman in 2019
20 maybe maybe a little bit later 2020.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. And so it's been a long time since
computer vision has been superhuman. And
so the prediction was radiologists would
go away because studying radiology scans
was thing of the past. AI will do that.
Well, they were absolutely right.
Computer vision is completely
superhuman. Every radiology platform and
package today is driven by AI.
And yet the number of radiologists grew.
And so the question is why? And we now
have a shortage of radiologists in the
world. And so one the alarmist
warning went too far and has scared
people from
doing this profession that is so
important to society. And so it did
harm. Now why was it wrong? The reason
why is because the purpose of a
radiologist, the purpose is to diagnose
disease and help patients and doctors
diagnose disease.
And because we're able to study scans so
much faster now, you could study more
scans. You could diagnose better. You
could you could um impatient faster. We
can see people more. the hospitals are
making more money. You have more
patients in the hospital. You need more
radiologists. I mean the the amazing
thing is it's so obvious this was going
to happen. The number of software
engineers at NVIDIA is going to grow,
not decline.
And the reason for that is because the
purpose of a software engineer and the
task of a software engineer for coding
are related, not the same. I wanted my
software engineers to solve problems. I
didn't care how many lines of code they
wrote.
You know, but their job, their purpose
of their job didn't change. Solving
problems, working as a team, diagnosing
problems, evaluating the result, looking
for new problems to solve innovation,
connecting dots, you know, none of that
stuff is going to go away.
>> So, you think it's possible that let's
even take coding, you think the number
of programmers in the world might
increase, not decrease?
>> And the reason for that is this. What is
the definition of coding?
I believe that is the definition coding
as of today is simply specifying
specification and maybe if you want to
be rather directive you could even give
it an architecture of the software that
you're you wanted to write. So the
question is how many people could do
that? Describe a specification for a
computer to go telling the computer what
to go build. How many people? I think we
just went from 30 million to probably 1
billion.
And so every every carpenter in the
future will be a coder. Except a
carpenter with AI is also an architect.
They just increased the value that they
could deliver to the customer. Their
their
artistry just elevated tremendously.
I believe that every accountant is, you
know, also your financial analyst, also
your financial adviser. So all of these
professions have just been elevated and
if I were a carpenter, I sees a I see
AI, I would just completely go berserk.
You know, the services I can bring to my
clients, if I were a plumber, completely
go berserk. and the the people that are
currently programmers and software
engineers, I think they're at the
cutting edge of understanding
intuitively how to communicate
with the agents using natural language
in order to design the best kind of
software.
>> That's right. So over time they'll
converge but I think uh there's still
value in getting I think uh learning how
to program like learning what
programming languages are uh the old the
old kind of programming uh what what are
good practices for programming languages
what are design principles for
programming languages for large software
systems
>> and and the reason for that lex and you
know I just say for the audience I think
the goal of the goal of specification,
the artistry of specification, the goal
and the artistry of it um is going to
depend on what problem you're trying to
solve. when I'm thinking when I'm
thinking about giving the company
strategies and um formulating corporate
directions and things that we should do
um I describe it at a level that is
sufficiently
specific that people generally
understand the direction and it's
actionable they it's so specific enough
that they can take action on it but I
underspecify it on purpose so that
enable 43 3,000 amazing people to make
it even better than I imagined.
And so when I'm working with engineers,
when I'm working with people, um, I
think about who what problem am I trying
to solve? Who am I working with?
And the level of specification, the
level of architecture definition
relates to that. And and so
everybody's going to have to learn how
where in the spectrum of coding they
want to be. Writing a specification is
coding. And so you might decide to be
quite prescriptive because there's a
very specific outcome you're looking
for. You might decide that you know this
is an area you want to be much more
exploratory. And so you might
underspecify and enable you to go back
and forth with the AI to even push your
own boundaries of creativity. And so
this artistry of where you are in the
spectrum, this is the future of coding.
>> But just to linger on it, outside of
coding, I think a lot of people
rightfully so
uh are worried about their jobs, have a
lot of anxiety about their jobs,
especially in the white collar sector.
[gasps and sighs]
Um I don't think any of us know
what to do
uh with tumultuous times that always
come when automations and new technology
arrives. And I just
first of all I think um
we all need to have compassion and the
responsibility to feel sort of the
burden of what the actual suffering
feels like for individual people and
families that lose their job. I think
whenever you have transformative
technology like that's coming with with
artificial intelligence, there's going
to be a lot of pain and I don't know
what to do about that uh pain.
Hopefully, it creates much more
opportunities for those same people uh
for the same kind of job as uh the
tooling evolves and makes them more
productive and makes it more fun
hopefully as it does in the programming.
I've I haven't I've been having so much
fun programming, I have to say. like
I've never had this much fun. So
hopefully it makes their job automates
the boring parts and makes the creative
parts uh the ones that the the human
beings are responsible for. But still
there's going to be a lot of pain and
suffering. So my first recommendation
before and this is now how I deal with
anxiety. In fact, we just talked about
it earlier.
>> Mhm.
>> Enormous anxiety about the future,
enormous anxiety about the pressure,
enormous anxiety about uncertainty.
I first break it down and then I'm going
to tell myself,
okay, there are some things you can do
something about. There are some things
you can't do anything about, but for the
stuff that you can do something about,
let's reason reason about it and let's
go do it.
>> If we were to hire a new college
graduate today and I have a choice
between two, one that have that is no
clue what AI is and one that is expert
in using AI. I would hire the one who's
expert in using AI. If I had an
accountant, a marketing person, the one
that is expert in using AI, supply
chain, customer service, a salesperson,
business development, a lawyer,
I would hire the one who is expert in
using AI. And so I would I would advise
that every college student, every every
teacher should encourage their student
to to go use AI. Every college student
should graduate and be an expert in AI.
And every everybody, if you're a
carpenter, if you're, you know,
electrician, go use AI. Go see what it
can do to transform your current job.
Elevate yourself. If I were a farmer, I
would absolutely use AI. If I were a
pharmacist, pharmacist, I would use AI.
I want to see how what it could do to
elevate my job so that I could be the I
could be the innovator to revolutionize
this industry myself.
>> And so that that would be the first
thing that I would do. And and then I
would also I would also help them. Um it
is the case that the technology will
dislocate and will eliminate many tasks.
If and because it will automate it. If
your job is the task if your job is the
task then you're very highly going to be
disrupted.
If your
job's purpose includes you certain
tasks. Mhm.
>> Then it it's vital that you go learn how
to use AI to automate those tasks. And
then there's the world of spectrum in
between.
>> And by the way, the beautiful thing
about AI, so the the the chatbot
versions
is you can break down you have anxiety
and you can break down the problem by
talking to it. [laughter] Like I've I've
recently it's really just incredible how
much you can think through your life's
problems and through and I don't mean
like therapy problems. I mean like very
practically, okay, I'm worried about my
literally I'm worried about my job. What
are the skills? What are the steps I
need to take? How do I get better at AI?
Everything you just said, you can
literally ask and it's going to give you
a point by point. I mean, it's just a
great life coach. Period. This
>> I don't know how to use AI. And the AI
goes, well, let me show you.
>> Exactly. [laughter] It's very meta, but
it's
>> it's kind of incredible. So, people
definitely should.
>> You can't walk up to Excel and say, I
don't know how to use Excel. You're
done. I mean that's really what AI has
done for me in all walks of life is that
initial friction of being a beginner of
using a thing for the first time. I can
literally ask about any single thing.
>> What are the first steps I need to take?
>> That's right.
>> And and that that handholding that it
does removing the friction of uh all the
experiences that the world offers is you
know like like I mentioned to you
offline you mentioned I'm I'm going to
China and Taiwan.
>> So awesome.
for you. Where do I go? What where do I
go? How do I all those questions
immediately answered and it's beautiful?
>> Well, when you when you go to Taiwan,
just ask AI, what are Jensen's favorite
restaurants in Taiwan?
>> Yeah.
>> And it'll actually Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> Is it accurate? Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. All right.
>> It's all over all over Taiwan.
>> Well, you're you're a rock star over
there and um and like we also mentioned
offline, maybe our paths will cross,
which would be really wonderful in
Computex GTC Taiwan.
Uh do you think there are some things
about human nature about human
consciousness
that is
fundamentally non-computational
maybe something a chip no matter how
powerful uh can never replicate? I don't
know if the chip will ever get nervous
and that's the you know of course the
conditions by which uh that causes
anxiety or nervousness or whatever
emotion um I believe that AI will be
able to recognize those and understand
those. I don't think my chips will feel
those and therefore the how how that
anxiety, how that feeling, how that
excitement, how that how that you know
all of those feelings manifest in human
performance for example extremely
amazing human performance, athletic
performance, you know, average or lesser
than average. um that that entire
spectrum of human performance that comes
out of exactly the same circumstances
for different people manifesting in
different outcome
manifesting in different performance. I
I don't think there's anything about
anything that we're building that would
suggest that two different computers
being presented with all of exactly the
same context would per of course it
would produce statistically different
outcomes but it's not because it felt
different.
>> Yeah. The subjective
boy there's something truly special
about the subjective experience
that we humans feel. Like I mentioned to
you, I was I was I was pretty nervous
talking to you like I mentioned to you
that the hope the fear the anxiety and
just life itself the richness of life
how amazing everything is how deeply we
fall in love how deeply our hearts get
broken how afraid we are of death and
how much pain we feel when our loved
ones pass away all of that the whole
thing I don't it's very hard to think AI
being able to a computational device
being able to do that but there's so
many mysteries about this whole thing
that we're yet to uncover that I am open
to be surprised.
>> I've been surprised a lot over the past
[snorts]
>> few months and few years. Scaling can
create some incredible miracles in the
space of intelligence
>> has been truly marvelous to watch. So
I'm open to surprise
>> and and it's just really important to to
break down what is intelligence and the
word that word we use all the time. It's
not a mysterious word. Intelligence has
a meaning, you know,
>> and it's a system that, you know, it's
it it's something that we do that in
includes perception and understanding
and reasoning and the ability to do plan
and you know that that loop that loop is
is um the fundamentally what
intelligence is. Intelligence is not one
word that is exactly equal to humanity.
And that's I think it's really important
to separate the two. We have two words
for that. I'm not I don't over fantasize
about and I don't over romanticize about
intelligence. Intelligence is and people
have heard me say it before. I actually
think intelligence is a commodity.
I'm surrounded by intelligent people.
And I'm surrounded by intelligent people
more intelligent than I am in each one
of the spaces that they're in. And yet I
have a role in that circle. It's
actually kind of interesting.
They're more educated than I am.
They went to better schools than I did.
They're deeper than in any in this field
that they're in. All of them. I have 60
of them. They're all superhuman to me.
>> And somehow I'm sitting in the middle
orchestrating all 60 of them. And so you
got to ask yourself,
what is what is it about a dishwasher
that allows that dishwasher to sit in
the middle of superhumans?
Does that make sense?
>> And so, but that's my point. My point is
intelligence is a is a functional thing.
Humanity is not a not specified
functionally.
It's a much much bigger word. and and
our life experience, our tolerance for
pain, our determination,
those are those are different words in
intelligence. And so the the thing that
I I want to help the audience
understand, if I could give them one
thing is is intelligence is a word that
we've elevated to very high form over
time. the the word we should really
elevate is humanity, character,
humanity, all of those things,
compassion, generosity,
all of the things that you say just now,
>> I believe those are superhuman powers
and that now intelligence is going to be
commoditized because we've spoken about
it. The most important thing is your
education. The most now even even when
they said the most important thing is
your education. when you went to school,
there's more than just knowledge that
you gained.
>> And so, but unfortunately, our society
had put everything into one single word.
And life is more than one word. And I'm
just telling you, my life would suggest
that being lower
on the intelligence curve than everybody
around me doesn't change the fact I'm
the most successful. And so [laughter]
and and I think I think that that kind
of is I'm trying hopefully to inspire
everybody else that don't let this de
democratization of intelligence, this
commoditization of intelligence,
you know, cause you anxiety. You should
be inspired by that.
>> Yeah. I I I think uh AI will help us
celebrate humans more. And I'm certainly
humanity and human first. And I I think
what makes this world incredible is
humans forever will be so. And just AI
is this incredible tool that makes us
>> That's exactly right.
>> Humans more powerful.
>> Uh so much of the success of Nvidia
and um the lives of millions of people
that I mentioned uh depend on you.
Uh but you're just one human like we
mentioned u mortal like all of us. Do
you think about your mortality? Are you
afraid of death?
>> I really don't want to die. Um, I have a
great life. I have a great family.
I have really important work.
Uh,
this is this is not a once in a once in
a lifetime experience suggests that it
has been experienced by many people just
not one person. Uh this is a once in a
humanity experience what I'm going
through. Uh Nvidia is one of the most
consequential technology companies in
history. We're doing very important
work. I take it very seriously.
Um
and and so some of the some of the
things that that of course are are
practical things like how do we think
about succession planning and and um I
I'm famous in saying that I don't
believe in succession planning
and and the reason the reason for that
the reason for that isn't because I'm
immortal. Um the reason for that is
because if you're worried about
succession planning, if you're worried
all that anxiety of succession planning,
then what should you do about it? Then
you break it all the way back down. The
most important thing you should do today
if you care about the future of your
company post you is to pass on
knowledge, information, insight, skills,
experience as often and continuously as
you can. which is the reason why I
continuously reason about everything in
front of my team. Every single meeting
is about a reasoning meeting. Every
moment I spend inside a company, outside
the company is about passing on
knowledge to people as fast as I can.
Nothing I learn ever sits on my desk
longer than, you know, a fraction of a
second. I'm passing that information,
that know. Oh my gosh, this is cool.
Before I even finish learning all of it
myself, I've already pointing it to
somebody else. get on this. This is so
cool. You're going to want to you're
going to want to learn this. And so I'm
constantly passing knowledge, empowering
people, elevating the capability of
everybody around me so that
um the outcome that I that I seek that I
hope for is that I die on the job, you
know, and and hopefully I die on the job
instantaneously. You [laughter]
and there's no long periods of
suffering, you know. Well, from a fan
perspective, [laughter]
given your your uh extremely
um your enormous positive impact on on
civilization, of course, I hope you keep
going, but also it's just fun to watch
what is [laughter] doing. You're, you
know, it's just the rate of innovation
and I'm a huge fan of engineering. It's
so much incredible engineering is
continuously being done by Nvidia. It's
just fun to watch. It's a celebration of
humanity. is a celebration of great
builders, a celebration of great
engineering. So it represents something
special. Uh so I hope uh you and Nvidia
keep going. What gives you hope about
this whole thing we got going on about
humanity? About the future of humanity
when you look out and you think about
the future quite a bit when you look out
10, 20, 50, 100 years from now, what
gives you hope? I I've always had I've
always had uh uh great confidence in in
the in the kindness
uh the generosity
uh
um the compassion, the human capacity.
I've always been extremely confident of
that. sometimes um
more so than I should and and I I get
taken advantage of. But it doesn't it
doesn't ever cause me not to. I start
with always
uh that that people want want to do
good. People want to um uh help others
and
uh vastly I am proven right,
constantly proven right and and often
uh exceeds my expectations
and and so I have complete confidence in
the human capacity.
I think the the the thing that the
things that give me incredible hope
is what I see as as I extrapolate as I
what I see now is possible and as I
extrapolate
um based on the things that we're doing
what will very likely happen
>> and and um and that there's so many
things that we want to solve there's so
many problems we want to solve there's
so any things that we want to build.
There's so many good things that we want
to do that are now within our reach and
within the reach of my my lifetime. You
just can't possibly not be romantic
about that. You know what I'm saying?
>> Yeah. What an exciting time to be alive.
>> Yeah.
>> Like truly truly. So
>> how can you not be romantic about about
about that? the the the fact that that
there is a there it's a reasonable thing
to expect the end of disease. It's a
reasonable thing to expect. It's a
reasonable thing to expect that
pollution will be drastically reduced.
It's a reasonable thing to expect that
traveling at the speed of light is
actually in our future. And then you
know not not for long distances but
short distances you know you people ask
me how you well first of all very soon
I'm going to put a humanoid on a
spaceship and it's going to be you know
my humanoid and and we're going to send
it out as soon you know as soon as
possible and it's going to keep
improving and enhancing along the flight
>> and then when it's time
all of the all of my consciousness has
already been you know so much of my life
has been uploaded in the internet take
all my inbox take everything that I've
done, everything I've said, you know,
it's been collect and be becoming my AI
and um I'm just, you know, when the time
comes, you know, we just send that at
the speed of light, catch up with my
robot.
[laughter]
Oh, that's brilliant. I mean, but for
me, that's sort of application focused,
[laughter]
but also for me the curiosity
uh maxing perspective, I just all of
those mysteries. It's so much
fascinating scientific questions there.
Understanding the biological machine is
is right around the corner. It's it's
not 10 years. It's 5 years probably.
>> And then your biological machine, the
the human mind and cracking physics,
theoretical physics open. It's so
exciting.
>> Explaining consciousness, that one would
be awesome
>> and it's all within our reach.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh Jensen, thank you so much for
everything you've done over the years.
Thank you for everything you're doing
for the world. Thank you for being who
you are. Uh, I can tell you're a great
human being and uh, I wish you
incredible success this year. I can't
wait as a fan. I can't wait to see what
you do next and hopefully I'll see you
in Taiwan. And thank you so much for
talking today.
>> Thank you, Lex. I had a great time and
and also if I could just say one more
thing
>> and thank you for all the interviews
that you do, the depth, the the respect
that you go through with and the
research that you do uh to reveal, you
know, for all of us, uh the the amazing
people that you've interviewed over the
years. I've enjoyed I I've enjoyed them
immensely and and and as an innovator to
have created this long form unbelievable
and and yet you know it's just
captivating. So anyways, thank you for
everything you do.
>> It means the world. Thank you, Jess.
>> Thank you, Lex. Thank you for listening
to this conversation with Jensen Kuang.
To support this podcast, please check
out our sponsors in the description
where you can also find links to contact
me, ask questions, give feedback, and so
on. And now let me leave you with some
words from Alan K.
The best way to predict the future is to
invent it.
Thank you for listening and hope to see
you next time.